<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Arvi's Blog</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://arg0s.in/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in" />
<updated>2015-07-28T01:59:41+00:00</updated>
<id>http://arg0s.in/</id>
<author>
  <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
  <uri>http://arg0s.in/</uri>
  <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Lean Startup Is Hard In Practice]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/why-lean-startup-is-hard-in-practice.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/why-lean-startup-is-hard-in-practice</id>
  <published>2015-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2015-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#why-lean-startup-is-hard-in-practice&quot;&gt;Why Lean Startup Is Hard In Practice&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#experiment-design-is-hard-for-beginners&quot;&gt;Experiment design is hard for beginners.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sampling-sizes-need-to-be-large-enough-to-hold-significance&quot;&gt;Sampling sizes need to be large enough to hold significance.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#managing-control-variables-across-experiment-batches-requires-rigor-and-persistence&quot;&gt;Managing control variables across experiment batches requires rigor and persistence.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#risk-of-missing-big-opportunities&quot;&gt;Risk of missing big opportunities.&lt;/a&gt;        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#effectuation-and-lean-startup&quot;&gt;Effectuation and Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#slope-of-enlightenment&quot;&gt;Slope of Enlightenment?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-lean-startup-is-hard-in-practice&quot;&gt;Why Lean Startup Is Hard In Practice&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last couple of years, I’ve blogged about my &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp.html&quot;&gt;lean startup experiments&lt;/a&gt; (a popular post that made page one of HN). I’ve spoken at conferences about applying lean to &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp.html&quot;&gt;building mobile apps&lt;/a&gt;. And, I was a mentor at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/why-im-a-mentor-at-lean-startup-machine-bangalore.html&quot;&gt;Lean Startup Machine&lt;/a&gt;. Along the way, I’ve applied lean at my last startup across ideas incubated using an internal Y-Combinator incubation format. I’ve collaborated with other entrepreneurs as a part of a DHC lean peer group (who reviewed this post). And right now, I’m running lean experiments at Intuit, a large software company. I’ve come to the conclusion that while lean startup has been a terrific step forward in how we think about what to build next, there’s still many significant challenges involved in practice. This post is an attempt to surface some of the issues so that we can talk about them as a community, and we can learn from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you read on, you may want to get past some of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.startuplessonslearned.com/2010/04/five-myths-about-lean-startup.html&quot;&gt;common misconceptions&lt;/a&gt; about Lean Startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;experiment-design-is-hard-for-beginners&quot;&gt;Experiment design is hard for beginners.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may seem obvious, but it’s worth mentioning. Some folks get into lean startup thinking of it in the context of cost, but that’s a misnomer. While &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_manufacturing&quot;&gt;lean manufacturing&lt;/a&gt; is about cost, and is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lean_startup#Origins&quot;&gt;origin&lt;/a&gt; of Eric Ries’ idea, Lean Startup is about translating a vision into a falsifiable business model hypothesis. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crafting a hypothesis and finding your leap of faith needs discipline. Choices about validation criteria can be subjective and need judgment calls. Decisions about how minimal your MVP needs to be can be challenging with marketplace or mobile apps where experience matters. Is the right experiment broad based generative research or evaluative to find fitment? Are we testing for the market needs or product fitment? That said, there’s certainly a wealth of information out there now, and vibrant supportive community that’s making this easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a alt=&quot;lean startup&quot; href=&quot;https://grasshopperherder.com/what-type-of-lean-startup-experiment-should-i-run/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/the-lean-startup-playbook.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Source: grasshopperherder.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many tools that have emerged in the last few years like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leancanvas.com&quot;&gt;Lean Canvas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.javelin.com/experiment-board.html&quot;&gt;Javelin Board&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leanmonitor.com/&quot;&gt;Lean Monitor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://leanlab.io/&quot;&gt;Lean Lab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leanlaunchlab.com/&quot;&gt;Lean Launch Lab&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intuitbrainstorm.com/&quot;&gt;Brainstorm&lt;/a&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://leanstack.com/&quot;&gt;Lean Stack&lt;/a&gt;. There’s even a clever &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.playinglean.com/&quot;&gt;board game&lt;/a&gt; by Simen Fure Jørgensen. There’s also several consultants and trainers offering training to help new entreprenurs or intrapreneurs apply lean startup to new ideas. While these have eased the learning curve somewhat, it’s still hard for a beginner going beyond a launch page and into his first pivot to figure out what next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sampling-sizes-need-to-be-large-enough-to-hold-significance&quot;&gt;Sampling sizes need to be large enough to hold significance.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, you’d want to go out and find your ideal customer whose pain your can solve well, and then find more like them. In practice, the narrative isn’t quite as linear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are looking for a strong signal, but looking to test with a minimal experience, you often look for early adopters whose pain is deep enough that they would use your MVP regardless of polish. Often, it can be a challenge finding enough early adopters who match your persona to test things at scale. What then happens is, conversions rates can tend to be lower if the sampling set includes mainstream users used to refined apps with a well designed experience. One way to address this is to craft an experiment that tests if improved design bumps up conversion numbers, but this poses a judgment call about whether you have sufficient validation to invest in further refinement. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can argue that this is all about distribution. While distribution is always a challenge for startups working through different channels for traction, these challenges exist in larger companies too. Larger organizations can be defensive about exposing key influential users (who are often early adopters) to scrappy experiments, making acquisition just as challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what ends up happening? Some run experiments with broad, large sampling sizes whose personas type may be a mismatch, leading to invalidation. Or, run with smaller groups with qualitative feedback that yields deeper insights, but may not be statistically significant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether choosing criteria for validation or making a pivot vs persevere decision, we’re often faced with situations that require a judgment call. Despite our best intentions, our decisions are often swayed by our biases. While our understanding of cognitive psychology may have improved over the year, we often let our biases get the better of us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/quotes/1249307-if-you-torture-the-data-long-enough-it-will-confess&quot;&gt;If you torture the data long enough, it will confess.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we often spend endless analyzing things, and make ourselves believe we are arriving at deeper insights by armchair analysis. Instead, we are often just rationalizing our own thoughts with dialectical skills. While Lean Startup provides a framework that appears to helps reduce otherwise rampant &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias&quot;&gt;confirmation bias&lt;/a&gt;, it doesn’t necessarily provide all the answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;managing-control-variables-across-experiment-batches-requires-rigor-and-persistence&quot;&gt;Managing control variables across experiment batches requires rigor and persistence.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common challenge I’ve seen has been identifying the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Control_variable#In_an_experiment&quot;&gt;control variables&lt;/a&gt; that influence your experiments and managing them across experiment batches. Without this in place, it can be hard to draw a strong correlation, and understand if you were invalidated or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, it’s easy to mix up testing out a channel hypothesis with a value hypothesis and get muddled. One of the medical startups that was at Lean Startup Machine went out and spoke to ten people on the street to test their initial value hypothesis. They got a lukewarm signal, but decided to persevere with a modified value hypothesis. They then went out and spoke to ten people at hospitals. Since the signal was weak, they felt they were invalidated, but weren’t sure if their original value prop might have appealed to the hospital. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In scientific lab experiments, control variables are carefully managed. If an experiment is run again with the same setup, the same results are expected. If not, the original experiment is usually considered to have been flawed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, tests in the real world are exposed to several variables which are often beyond our control. While a scrappy approach helps us try things out quickly, keeping in mind the different control variables that apply to your experiment and holding them constant may help derive better inferences about the result of an experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;risk-of-missing-big-opportunities&quot;&gt;Risk of missing big opportunities.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it was &lt;a href=&quot;http://blakemasters.com/post/23435743973/peter-thiels-cs183-startup-class-13-notes&quot;&gt;Peter Thiel&lt;/a&gt; who opined that we may have swung too far from ‘determinate optimism’ towards ‘indeterminate optimism’. He appears to believe that the Lean Startup approach of attempting small bets make not really translate into big high impact ideas that can disrupt industries. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Indefinite futures are inherently iterative. You can’t plan them out; things just unfold on top of each other. The question is thus whether an iterative process can lead, if not to the best of all possible worlds, at least to a world where there is a path of monotonic and potentially never-ending improvement. If it can, we may not get to the tallest mountain in the universe. But at least we’ll always go uphill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put simply, he doesn’t think you can experiment your way towards a grand vision. But on the other hand, many great startup ideas that seem visionary now sounded terrible when they started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Iteration and machine learning are often excuses for not thinking about the future and short time horizons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/thiel.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of his thought process there is that post the 2008 subprime crisis, the world has largely slipped away from the top left quadrant towads the bottom half. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;effectuation-and-lean-startup&quot;&gt;Effectuation and Lean Startup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also the views of Professor &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.darden.virginia.edu/faculty-research/directory/saras-d-sarasvathy/&quot;&gt;Saras Sarasvathy&lt;/a&gt;, who was a speaker at a fabulous &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ispirt.in/&quot;&gt;iSprt&lt;/a&gt; roundtable last year. Saras’s paper on “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.effectuation.org/sites/default/files/documents/what-makes-entrepreneurs-entrepreneurial-sarasvathy.pdf&quot;&gt;What makes entrepreneurs entrepreneurial&lt;/a&gt;” is now regarded as a seminal piece on &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Effectuation&quot;&gt;Effectuation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/means-causal-vs-effectual.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Source: effectuation.org&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In simple terms, her view is that causal reasoning is used when the future is predictable. But effectual reasoning is used when the future is unpredictable, which is most often the case for entrepreneurs. She believes that instead of causal or systems thinking, entrepreneurs look to leverage available resources at hand to see where they can go from there. In many ways, some of her ideas resonated with the audience and &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; more intuitive than Lean Startup. Some, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://thestartuptoolkit.com/blog/2014/09/i-prefer-effectuation-to-lean-startup-sorta/&quot;&gt;Rob Fitzpatrick&lt;/a&gt; have opined that Effectuation may be the better suited tool to decide &lt;a href=&quot;http://thestartuptoolkit.com/blog/2014/09/i-prefer-effectuation-to-lean-startup-sorta/&quot;&gt;what to do next&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, most of these views are inherently hard to digest since there’s no easy way to examine how any of these approaches are working in practice. While there are some people who claim to have succeeded using one framework or the other, those declarations have mostly come &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; they achieved success with limited visibility into the journey. Are we just falling for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Survivorship_bias&quot;&gt;survivorship bias&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;slope-of-enlightenment&quot;&gt;Slope of Enlightenment?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;10/Founders and employees often have running room to try multiple products within a single startup; hence popularity of the term &amp;quot;pivot&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Marc Andreessen (@pmarca) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pmarca/status/580499614207492096&quot;&gt;March 24, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;That &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pmarca&quot;&gt;@pmarca&lt;/a&gt; storm emphasizes two key ideas: founders can gain portfolio economics via 1. pivots and 2. making entrepreneurship a career&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Eric Ries (@ericries) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ericries/status/580501556073766912&quot;&gt;March 24, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like we are past the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hype_cycle&quot;&gt;peak of inflated expectations&lt;/a&gt; around lean startup. But are we on to the slope of enlightenment quite yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irrespective of whether we are in a startup or a big company, we’ve come a long way in the last decade with how we think about building products. Lean Startup has radically changed how we think about taking a new idea forward. While there are challenges, it’s great that there is an active community that shares ongoing experiments and trades notes. Continuing to do this will help us learn from each other, and continue to refine our working models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/lean-startup-hype-cycle.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now well beyond thinking of lean startup solely in terms of cost saving, or an excuse to put out half assed MVPs, or to keep pivoting at a whim. If you believe the traction Eric seems to have around his new book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/881308232/only-on-kickstarter-the-leaders-guide-by-eric-ries&quot;&gt;The Leader’s Guide&lt;/a&gt;, a significant community has embraced Lean Startup in the context of both entrepreneurship and intrapreneurship across a wide range of industries. While challenges remain, we continue to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We cannot afford to have our success breed a new pseudoscience around pivots, MVPs, and the like. This was the fate of scientific management, and in the end, I believe, that set back its cause by decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have suggestions or examples from your experiences, please drop me a note or connect via Twitter @twitortat.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/why-lean-startup-is-hard-in-practice.html&quot;&gt;Why Lean Startup Is Hard In Practice&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on June 01, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Second PyCon]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/my-second-pycon.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/my-second-pycon</id>
  <updated>2014-10-11 04:53:16 UTCT00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/lifeofpy.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A decade back, college kids used to get taught assembly, C/C++ and Java. Javascript has taken over as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hanselman.com/blog/JavaScriptisAssemblyLanguagefortheWebPart2MadnessorjustInsanity.aspx&quot;&gt;assembly language of the web&lt;/a&gt;. And, the place of C/C++/Java in the educational institutions is now dominated by &lt;a href=&quot;http://cacm.acm.org/blogs/blog-cacm/176450-python-is-now-the-most-popular-introductory-teaching-language-at-top-us-universities/fulltext&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was honored to go from being a &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/my-first-PyCon.html&quot;&gt;speaker at last year’s PyCon&lt;/a&gt; to being a part of the &lt;em&gt;program committee&lt;/em&gt; for the 2014 PyCon which concluded in the last week of September. The Pycon conference is organized by PSSI, a community driven non-profit similar to PSF in the US. The program committee’s focus is primarily on the content of the conference, and assists with curation and mentoring speakers. The committee is a part of the &lt;em&gt;significantly&lt;/em&gt; larger volunteer driven organizing team which handles other aspects of sponsorship, logistics, food and setup. While I’d chaired the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/making-droidcon-bigger-better.html&quot;&gt;Droidcon committee&lt;/a&gt; earlier, this was a new experience in a very different tech community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my 10 highlights of the event. This is of course a personal account, and my views are my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;python-is-everywhere&quot;&gt;Python is Everywhere.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a privilege being a part of what is arguably one of India’s largest tech events, and one of the largest PyCon events around the world. I’m always amazed at how this little &lt;em&gt;microcosm&lt;/em&gt; of the python universe reminds us of how far and wide the language is used. Web programming. Machine learning. 3-D Modeling. Weather forecasting. Gaming. Education. Embedded Systems. 
	And in the local community, a wonderful effort has been initiated by Anand to expand Python Month to a year long initiative to help educate newbies with Python. Say hello to &lt;a href=&quot;pythonexpress.in&quot;&gt;Python Express&lt;/a&gt;. If you are a professor, a student or a trainer, I’d encourage you to consider signing up or seeing if there’s already a workshop happening close to where you live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;collaborating-with-an-amazing-program-committee&quot;&gt;Collaborating with an amazing Program Committee.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core program committee consisted of Krace, Konark, Kushal, Senthil and I. We were faced with the challenge of having to look at the 140+ submissions and choose around 20 from them. This ended up being incredibly hard since there were several excellent proposals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rough-approach&quot;&gt;Rough Approach.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the rough approach we took, and a full account deserves a formal post on the PyCon blog. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Between us, we broke out the different sections of submissions for review with a primary and secondary owner for each section. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This let us divide and conquer so that each person need not review more than 30-40 proposals. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We would read through the abstracts, go through slides (where available), request past speaker videos, and go through upstream contributions. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having a primary and secondary owner reduced the bias that a single reviewer may have, although it’s hard to completely avoid group think. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To the extent that was possible, we interacted with people via the submission funnel, requesting additional information and posting feedback. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Based on this, we shortlisted about 30 odd speakers, including a few who were waitlisted. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We then rigorously followed up with each individual speaker to whet their slides, talk through their presentation structure, demo content, and key takeaways for the audience. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were supported by Noufal and Anand who joined us on a number of the hangouts we organized every few weeks to ensure we were on the same page, and had consensus on key decisions being made. Senthil, in addition to his review of core and embedded content, also drove the workshops. Pratap and Kathir were external reviewers who helped with inputs of the scientific computing submissions since the committee didnt have sufficient experience internally. Vijay, in addition to several other duties running the conference, helped put together most of the schedule. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, here are some structured guidelines we put together for the speakers. If you’d like to view the full 12 page slidedeck, it’s up here on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/aravindkrishnaswamy/PyCon-india-2014-10-tips-for-speakers&quot;&gt;SlideShare&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;images/conference-speaker-tips.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feedback ratings post conference show a significant improvement from the previous years ratings. Apart from two talks, all the other talks had relatively positive ratings, and a handful had high ratings. So we must have been doing something right with several long hours in our spare time that went into this. That said, there’s still lots of room for improvement, and there always will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;original-work&quot;&gt;Original Work.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session by Sandeep on an &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/sandeepraju/sharq-an-open-source-rate-limited-queueing-system-PyCon-india-2014&quot;&gt;Sharq&lt;/a&gt;, open source rate limited queueing system he’d built was one of the standout sessions of the conference. It wasn’t one of the most popular sessions, and it mostly attracted a niche crowd. But where it stood out, was in terms of &lt;em&gt;original work&lt;/em&gt; that had been done. I had a chance to check out his work before the conference, and played around with it. Although unacknowledged, it may be partly derived from work by &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/52569901&quot;&gt;Alan Shreve&lt;/a&gt; (whose work is however not open sourced). It’d be great to see more people in the community come forward and show off their original work, and perhaps more importantly, leverage the conference platform to find others to collaborate with and build on each others good work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conferences-are-fun&quot;&gt;Conferences are fun.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heh, we even found time to shake a gangnam leg on stage for posterity later in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/pycancan.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kushals-keynote&quot;&gt;Kushal’s Keynote.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kushaldas&quot;&gt;Kushal&lt;/a&gt; delivered a &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; keynote that chronicled his journey. From his beginnings in his village, through learning technology, contributing upstream, learning from others around him, coaching and mentoring others, it was a wonderful journey told straight from the heart. If you haven’t look up the excellent work &lt;a href=&quot;http://dgplug.org/&quot;&gt;DgpLUG&lt;/a&gt; now does - they have their unofficial(?) annual meeting on the stairway at PyCon. I was sitting with him just minutes before he got started with the keynote, and he wanted me to look through his slides. As he started to walk me through them, I had to interrupt him - I was so touched by the first few slides that I selfishly told him that I wanted to just hear him live on stage. I’d like to think I made up for that by clicking him in this Moses pose, parting the upstream waters for aspiring contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;images/kushal-upstream.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure Kiran’s keynote last year and Kushal’s this year will inspire several to think &lt;em&gt;upstream&lt;/em&gt;. I’d love to see more such personal stories that weave in key themes that set the tone for the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dinner-with-the-speakers&quot;&gt;Dinner with the Speakers.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did this smaller, intimate dinner with the speakers and volunteers on one of the evenings at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zomato.com/bangalore/barbeque-junction-koramangala&quot;&gt;Barbeque Junction&lt;/a&gt; in Koramangala. The food was passable, but the conversations were electric. I caught up with Sonal, Dhananjay and Vajrasky over dinner, and we had an enthralling discussion about work, travel, and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;old-faces-new-faces&quot;&gt;Old Faces, New Faces.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met a number of incredibly smart people, and I wish I could recall enough names to list them here. While some of the sessions were by veteran speakers, there were a couple of first time speakers. One of them that stood out was a session on Medusa, a Dart generator, that was presented by Rahul, a college student. I snuck out of the conference in between to go attend the Bangalore Literature Festival for a bit with Abhay, and apparently missed seeing a 9 year old present about his work with Arduino. It was also nice to meet familiar faces from previous PyCons and hang out on the stairway. I don’t know about more Audis, but the conference hall likely needs more stairways soon! Noufal. Anand. Kiran. Dhananjay. Sonal. Krace. Shrayas. Abhishek. Kushal. Anand. Sankarshan. Michael. Haris. Sandeep. Vajrasky. Abhay. And the many more whose names I cant remember now. Thanks for terrific conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;panel---flask-vs-django-vs-webpy&quot;&gt;Panel - Flask vs Django vs Web.py&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, I’ll admit I’m biased since I came up with the idea for this panel and I also moderated the discussion. After my talk on &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/my-first-PyCon.html&quot;&gt;Flask at last year’s PyCon&lt;/a&gt;, I got a number of questions about choosing the right framework. It’s often a nuanced choice, and there’s no one size fits all answer. I thought it would make for an engaging conversation in a debate style format to get the different tradeoffs involved directly from experienced practitioners. One of the things I didn’t want to do however was to script the panel discussion. I prepped the panelists so that a general sense of the structure of the discussion, and the high level themes were clear, but we avoided discussing specifics until we were on stage.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was nervous an hour before the panel. There were just a ton of little things to juggle. I skipped lunch to get set up on stage and prep. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to walk the difficult line between maintaining structure and retaining spontaneity. I kept the Twitter #pyconindia stream open on one screen along with my moderator notes, and the slides projected on the other. I wasn’t sure how well conference Wi-Fi would hold out, but I was going to meld in questions that came in via the Twitter hash tag into the panel itself. My moderator notes had specific questions, timelines for reach round of discussion, and icebreakers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was also important to engage with the panelists to ensure they had sufficient talk time on each point, and countered each others points. To make things a bit harder, we were on just after a big hearty lunch, and some amount of levity was essential to avoid the audience going into mass coma. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/panel-lineup.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved the energy of the debate, and I thought the three panelists - Anand, Kiran and Arun were outstanding. I think we are fortunate to have such experienced practitioners together on stage. Anand is a co-author and maintainer of Web.py and had collaborated with Aaron Swartz. Kiran has been using Flask at scale actively at HasGeek over the last few years. Arun is an acknowledged expert on Django and has a book coming out soon. I’m honored to have shared the stage with them that afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, it amused me how Kiran who had initially been on the fence about taking a strong position with Flask started thumping the Alchemy bible whenever Anand dissed ORMs. That got the audience really going. Arun was Django unchained, and held his ground throughout pretty well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d built a basic &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arg0s/ungli&quot;&gt;missed call voting system&lt;/a&gt; which we used at the end to poll the audience. 402 people voted via their phones in the space a minute. I was relieved that the system held up when it had to, although Wi-Fi dropped and we couldn’t project the live results. The clear winner was Django. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;images/panel-live.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;images/panel-votes.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During planning as well as setup, I received great inputs and suggestions from Krace, Konark and Mukesh. Also, Abhishek helped pull together the awesome visualization of the voting on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/darkyen/pen/dicgu&quot;&gt;codepen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-spaces&quot;&gt;Open Spaces!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We followed up the panel with a deep dive in the Open Space area upstairs at Nimhans. With a smaller group of 25-30 folks, it was a good opportunity to dig into the nuances a little more, talk about personal experiences, and also cover off frameworks like Pyramid and Twisted. The discussions could have been more interactive, but some of this will take time to evolve. I’ll likely spend more of my time in open spaces next year than in sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/stop.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pure-volunteer-magic&quot;&gt;Pure Volunteer Magic.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s incredible how much volunteer effort goes into the conference. Apparently there were over 1200+ delegates, which means a packaged house at the Nimhans venue. Volunteers worked round the clock the week of the conference to get the food, decorations, handouts, T-shirts, registration and sponsor booths, and a zillion little things right. With this being a volunteer driven event, there’s also a ton of chaos. Communication isn’t always great, a few people end up doing a sizeable chunk of the work, and a few things always fall through. But, it’s the self organizing nature of community events which makes them special and unique. The early bird price of the ticket for the event is INR 800 (USD 13), which is ridiculous value for the two days of great sessions, meeting smart people, eating scrumptious food, and getting a fun conference tee. In contrast, most other good tech events in Bangalore are often upwards of INR 3000 or more, and dont often include the swag. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life with Py is good! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/lifeofpy.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/my-second-pycon.html&quot;&gt;My Second PyCon&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on October 11, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why People Buy Things From You]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/why-people-buy-things-from-you.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/why-people-buy-things-from-you</id>
  <published>2014-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/why-people-buy-things.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/why-people-buy-things.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Why People Buy Things&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can spend a ton of time making your site easier for your customers to understand &lt;em&gt;what you do&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can spend a ton of time understanding your customers. And then customers will buy things from you because you understand &lt;em&gt;what they do&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/why-people-buy-things-from-you.html&quot;&gt;Why People Buy Things From You&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on June 06, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Customer Development, Invalidation, Karma and WhatsApp]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/customer-development-invalidation-karma-and-whatsapp.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/customer-development-invalidation-karma-and-whatsapp</id>
  <published>2014-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is an &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; story worth sharing again, and again. In May 2009, an entrepreneur shared this on an online forum that he was active on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wouldn’t it be cool if i just set a status for my iPhone, similar to how you can set a status on yahoo messenger or skype.  So i spent a couple of months and developed a little tool - it can let you set a status like “On the flight to munich, send email instead of calling me”. I would like to hear your feedback and suggestions on the idea. Hit or miss?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out, there was only one comment in response to his post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It appears that this requires the other party to also have the app installed, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bummer. The bubble just burst. But just a little bit later, in July `09, the entrepreneur is back with a new update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Just wanted to mention that version for blackberry is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No response on the forum. They were all like whatever, dude. But then, fastforward a few years to Sep `13, and the entrepreneur is back with this post on the same old thread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;so i was looking on this forum for something else (trying to use my M&amp;amp;M miles) and remembered i posted this thread 4 years ago. i am thinking some of you might be using WhatsApp now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jan_Koum&quot;&gt;Jan Koum&lt;/a&gt; had left Yahoo, and then taken time off to travel around South America. He then tried applying at Facebook, but got rejected. Later in Jan 2009, he came up on the app idea of Whatsapp, and started working on it. It didn’t click initially, but he hedged his bets and kept pushing along until the numbers started to grow. And the rest as they say, is history. Karma apparently works in mysterious ways, and Jan is back at Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/karma-whatsapp.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/karma-whatsapp.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Karma and Whatsapp&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worth pondering about what the MVP for Whatsapp would be. If you’d believe a random source below, the MVP costs $120,000, whatever that means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/mvp-whatsapp.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/mvp-whatsapp.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Is this really what it takes to build a Whatsapp MVP?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few questions worth asking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you think the MVP in this case is?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you followed a customer development approach and spoke to 20-30 people back in ‘09 about this like Jan did, it’s quite possible that most of them may have said they wouldn’t use it since it requires others to be on as well. If that had happened, what would your learning have been?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If building a community is a part of the MVP itself, how do you test that out as early as possible?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did Whatsapp succeed despite the existence of players like Google, Facebook, Skype and others with their messengers? Why were the telecom providers bleeding SMS revenue caught napping? What can we learn from it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/customer-development-invalidation-karma-and-whatsapp.html&quot;&gt;Customer Development, Invalidation, Karma and WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 29, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Evolution of the PMO Site - Vajpayee to Modi]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/the-evolution-of-the-pmo-site-vajpayee-to-modi.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/the-evolution-of-the-pmo-site-vajpayee-to-modi</id>
  <published>2014-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a colorful look back at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pmindia.nic.in/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PMO India site&lt;/a&gt; over the years, with archives from the Wayback Machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/namo/may-11-2000.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/namo/may-11-2000.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Vajpayee PMO site in May 2000. Not terrible for a site from the `90s, but still all over the place. Note the prominent poll on match fixing!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/namo/jun-2-2003.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/namo/jun-2-2003.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Vajpayee PMO site in June 2003. Polls on cricket continue. His poems are still prominently featured. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/namo/mar-30-2005.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/namo/mar-30-2005.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Manmohan PMO site in Mar 2005. Just the profile picture and name were switched.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/namo/jul-9-2007.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/namo/jul-9-2007.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Manmohan PMO site in Jul 2007. Highlights prominently the one thing he was never known for - his speeches.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/namo/jul-16-2011.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/namo/jul-16-2011.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Manmohan PMO site in Jul 2011. Six years in office and barely any changes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/namo/jan-22-2014.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/namo/jan-22-2014.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Manmohan PMO site in Jan 2014. A pre-election site rev to make his *cough* speeches more prominent.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/namo/may-26-2014.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/namo/may-26-2014.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Narendra Modi PMO site in May 2014. A snappy new site that went live at the time of the swearing in. Promises transparency and an channel for direct communication with the people.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The PMO &lt;a href=&quot;http://pmindia.nic.in/website_policy.php&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;website policy&lt;/a&gt; section indicates that external sites must get their permission before linking in to it. I’ve sent in a request for permission, but I hope this policy is just a relic of the old website that never did get updated. In case you are from NIC or PMO and would like the link removed, please &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/ask-me-anything/&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/the-evolution-of-the-pmo-site-vajpayee-to-modi.html&quot;&gt;The Evolution of the PMO Site - Vajpayee to Modi&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 27, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Large Companies Should Consider A Lean Startup Approach]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/why-large-companies-should-consider-a-lean-startup-approach.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/why-large-companies-should-consider-a-lean-startup-approach</id>
  <published>2014-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/Penenberg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Adam Penenberg&lt;/a&gt; made a great &lt;a href=&quot;http://pando.com/2014/04/18/dancing-giants-why-large-companies-should-embrace-the-minimum-viable-product&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; about large companies and why the MVP matters to them. There’s several things that I strongly agree with, but one stands out in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Large companies are still largely stepped in a culture that’s risk averse.&lt;/em&gt; They have large teams dedicated to building out and fine tuning processes within the organization for strategic planning and execution. As Adam says, the traditional mindset is biased towards more upfront planning, in the hope that more planning will translate into better results. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That is, the more planning we do, the more apt we are to hit the nail on the head. The more thought we put in upfront around designing the next product, the more apt we are to hit the mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; from the truth. Companies that build a business model or a large product based on a long cycle of planning, deliberation and analysis are only increasing their risk. While there are exceptions, they are far from the norm, and the reason why large companies today find it easier to acqui-hire than to innovate internally. The sooner we get ourselves in front of real users, talking to them, and getting data or feedback, the better placed we are to test out high risk assumptions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Infosys, which has seen a slew of top-level exits recently, saw attrition rise to 18.1%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder why Indian IT giants like Infosys, Cognizant, Wipro and TCS have made no headway whatsoever with their attempts at what they call non-linear growth models? The writing is very much on the wall. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great recession of `08 pretty much hammered in the last nails on large enterprise software and unwarranted custom development. While they’ve created teams focused on building solution frameworks and reusable software, they’ve not experimented with radical changes to their models. With most bright grads now moving to startups, you wonder how they can influence internal change any more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, our IT industry and education systems churn out graduates who are exceptionally good at solving &lt;em&gt;well defined problems&lt;/em&gt;. We’re also good at mapping undefined problems to certain known patterns and approaching them. However, we lack adeptness with lateral thinking and dealing with complete ambiguity in an open, exploratory mode. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cultivate a learning mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most of our ivory towers, there’s a great deal of emphasis on &lt;em&gt;strategic thinking&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;ability to execute&lt;/em&gt;, but an insufficient understanding of the importance of a &lt;em&gt;learning mindset&lt;/em&gt;. In contrast, graduates with an ability to cultivate and retain a learning mindset are most likely to be  enterpreneurs. Their natural tendency to run along with an open mind, be filling to adapt to the unknown, and leverage their intuition while there’s limited data at hand sets them apart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to see a few of the majors come forward and create venture funds, support the startup ecosystem, and encourage some of their intrapreneurs to take wing. With a &lt;em&gt;quarterly&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livemint.com/Companies/HCunTVSouBUdsakftRsgQP/Infosys-beats-profit-estimates-raises-revenue-guidance.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;net profit of $463 million&lt;/a&gt;, I’d imagine it wouldnt break the bank for Infosys to create a $100 million fund. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’d have to start by opening their minds.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/why-large-companies-should-consider-a-lean-startup-approach.html&quot;&gt;Why Large Companies Should Consider A Lean Startup Approach&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 22, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A 10 Minute Good Reads Challenge]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/a-10-minute-good-reads-challenge.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/a-10-minute-good-reads-challenge</id>
  <published>2014-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, my colleague and good friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/pub/raj-kannan/0/313/4a9&quot;&gt;Raj&lt;/a&gt; prodded me towards this post. He asked us to come up with a list few &lt;em&gt;memorable&lt;/em&gt; blog posts that we’d all liked. What constitutes a blog post was left fairly open, and could include opinion pieces from all types of media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-list&quot;&gt;The List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent all of 10 minutes pulling this together. (And then longer finding the right links online.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Super Successful Companies”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Sam Altman&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The debilitating myth of musical chairs”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Seth Godin&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Be Good”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Paul Graham&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Python And The Principle Of Least Astonishment”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Armin Ronacher&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Narendra Modi: Man of the Masses”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by William Dalrymple&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Licensing In A Post Copyright World”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Armin Ronacher&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“But What If I Fail”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Seth Godin&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The Powerlessness Of Positive Thinking”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Adam Alter&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The Most Beautiful Game”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Geoff Dyer&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“The End of Imagination”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; by Arundhati Roy&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-futility&quot;&gt;The Futility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list isn’t terrible, but it doesn’t capture some of the better reads I’ve come by. It’s mostly an incongruous cocktail of authors who have been in my mind lately. Sadly, my searches through Readability and Pocket to find memorable posts within those 10 minutes proved to be futile. It’s a reminder of how in this world where a barrage of information passes us by, we quickly get consumed by the deluge. Maybe it’s time to get back to bookmarking. Or, going back and re-reading old posts that we love. &lt;strike&gt;And scribbling notes on the side.&lt;/strike&gt; &lt;em&gt;Oh wait, can’t do that anymore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-unscience&quot;&gt;The Unscience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/pub/raj-kannan/0/313/4a9&quot;&gt;Raj&lt;/a&gt; hope to achieve out of this? Well, he’s been researching what he calls the &lt;strong&gt;unscience&lt;/strong&gt; behind blog posts - a science that’s not really a science. There’s a bit of a fad today where writers who appear to have no research or scientific background craft posts with a variant of science in the title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Science of Yada Yada&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What Science Tells Us About Yada Yada&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Scientific Reasons Why You Should Do Yada Yada&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The posts toss together a ton of what’s often pseudo science, but are aggregrated well and presented in a credible way. And these posts are quickly lapped up masses who don’t have the patience to dig into the details themselves. Ergo, the pseudo science becomes a science that’s believed in. Intrigued or puzzled? Read Raj’s post - &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.justshareapp.com/Unscience-of-Blogging/&quot;&gt;Unscience of Blogging&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’d like to take up the 10 minute good read challenge, make your list and link back here in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.samaltman.com/super-successful-companies&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“Super Successful Companies”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2014/03/the-debilitating-myth-of-musical-chairs.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;“The debilitating myth of musical chairs”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/good.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Be Good&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lucumr.pocoo.org/2011/7/9/python-and-pola/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Python And The Principle Of Least Astonishment&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lucumr.pocoo.org/2013/7/23/licensing/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Licensing In A Post Copyright World&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newstatesman.com/politics/2014/05/narendra-modi-man-masses&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Narendra Modi: Man of the Masses&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2014/01/but-what-if-i-fail.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;But What If I Fail&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/online/blogs/currency/2014/02/the-powerlessness-of-positive-thinking.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Powerlessness Of Positive Thinking&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prospectmagazine.co.uk/magazine/geoff-dyer-tennis-beautiful-game-federer/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Most Beautiful Game&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hindu.com/fline/fl1516/15160040.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The End of Imagination&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/a-10-minute-good-reads-challenge.html&quot;&gt;A 10 Minute Good Reads Challenge&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 20, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I'm a Mentor at Lean Startup Machine Bangalore]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/why-im-a-mentor-at-lean-startup-machine-bangalore.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/why-im-a-mentor-at-lean-startup-machine-bangalore</id>
  <published>2014-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
	&lt;header&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-lean-startup-movement&quot;&gt;The Lean Startup Movement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#practicing-lean&quot;&gt;Practicing Lean&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lsm-bangalore-mentors&quot;&gt;LSM Bangalore Mentors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-lsm-works&quot;&gt;How LSM works&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hackathons&quot;&gt;Hackathons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#validation-board&quot;&gt;Validation Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-takeaways-can-you-expect&quot;&gt;What takeaways can you expect?&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#say-hello&quot;&gt;Say Hello&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#slides&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;UPDATE: This post has been updated to include my slides further down at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lean Startup Machine is coming to Bangalore, India. LSM has held 150 workshops in 50 cities, across six continents, for over 25,000 aspiring entrepreneurs around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-lean-startup-movement&quot;&gt;The Lean Startup Movement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you’ve been living in a cave, you’ve likely noticed that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://theleanstartup.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lean Startup&lt;/a&gt; movement has been gaining momentum worldwide. Since &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.in/The-Lean-Startup-Entrepreneurs-Continuous/dp/0307887898&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eric Ries&lt;/a&gt; wrote about continous innovation, several startups have embraced a new way of building sustainable businesses. One of the misnomers associated with lean, especially amongst the uninitiated, is thinking that lean represents just a &lt;em&gt;capital efficient&lt;/em&gt; way of running a company. Instead, it’s 	a radical shift in &lt;em&gt;how we think&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practitioners go through a methodical set of steps. They start outlining their bright new idea and identifying their target customers. Next, they put down the high risk elements of their idea, and go about validating them with a series of iterations that involve direct customer feedback. They progress forward only after having gotten validation at each step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the lean approach does not guarantee success, it provides a systematic foundation for real learning and improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;practicing-lean&quot;&gt;Practicing Lean&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve blogged recently about what I’ve learnt about &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/lean-startup-customer-development-interviews.html&quot;&gt;customer development&lt;/a&gt;, applying &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/applying-lean-startup-principles-to-mobile-app-development.html&quot;&gt;lean to mobile app development&lt;/a&gt;, and learnings from an &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp.html&quot;&gt;MVP that we abandoned&lt;/a&gt;. A lot of it is plain common sense, and likely includes many things you already apply. I’ve found it valuable to have a structure around my thinking as well as a shared vocabulary since it helps me communicate my thought process and intuition better. I’ll continue to update my blog as I learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lsm-bangalore-mentors&quot;&gt;LSM Bangalore Mentors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently invited to volunteer as a mentor for young, upcoming entrepreneurs that are going through a 3-day workshop at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leanstartupmachine.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lean Startup Machine&lt;/a&gt;. LSM has held 150 workshops on lean methodology in 50 cities, across six continents, for over 25,000 aspiring entrepreneurs around the world. All the mentors volunteer their time, and pay it forward towards the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/lean-startup-machine-bangalore-mentors.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/lean-startup-machine-bangalore-mentors.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Lean Startup Machine Bangalore Startup Mentors&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an excellent line up. There’s several leading lean practitioners like &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mtrajan&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@mtrajan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mohamax&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@mohamax&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/natwar86&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@natwar86&lt;/a&gt;, who are all doing a wonderful job educating and supporting the local community. There’s successful enterpreneurs like &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/phan1881&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@phani1881&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/pratyushp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@pratyushp&lt;/a&gt; as well as VCs like &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/seedfund&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@seedfund&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/s_brij_verma&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@s_brij_verma&lt;/a&gt;. I’m chuffed to be in such good company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-lsm-works&quot;&gt;How LSM works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;images/lsm-about.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;The excerpt above is from the Lean Startup Machine About page&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/Qwh62zNgBaY?hd=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;autohide=1&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Melissa Peri on her Lean Startup Machine experience.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hackathons&quot;&gt;Hackathons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s worthwhile noting that the LSM workshop is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a hackathon. It’s less about coding, and more about teaching entrepreneurs and innovators about how to build products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;validation-board&quot;&gt;Validation Board&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Validation boards are tools to help enterprenurs apply lean methodologies. They provide a sheet which helps you structure your thinking with slots for your USP, target segment, revenue model, hypothesis, and learnings. A few popular boards include the &lt;a href=&quot;http://leanstack.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lean Canvas&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.leanstartupmachine.com/validationboard/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Javelin Experiment Board&lt;/a&gt;. Javelin, the organization that runs LSM worldwide recently &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.wsj.com/venturecapital/2014/03/05/javelin-raises-1-5m-to-bring-lean-startup-method-to-big-corporations/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;raised $1.5 million&lt;/a&gt;, and part of the agenda in the LSM workshops will be to orient you with their own tools. Related, but slightly different tools for managing your KanBan include &lt;a href=&quot;http://kanbantool.com/lean-startup-kanban&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lean Startup Kanban&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leankit.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;LeanKit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-takeaways-can-you-expect&quot;&gt;What takeaways can you expect?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network with several aspiring entrepreneurs in a small cohesive environment, far away from the noise of the startup conference dance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn how to adopt a systematic way of testing out your ideas to see if they solve real problems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand how getting out of your cubicle and talking to real users can help you seek validation about your ideas early, and help refine your MVP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practical examples of how other lean practitioners have benefited from the methodology, and  insights you can benefit from.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LSM tickets are $299 in the US, but are priced by the organizers, &lt;a href=&quot;http://10000startups.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nascomm 10000 Startups&lt;/a&gt; at Rs.3,500 (~$60) for the 3-day workshop. It’s a small fraction of the international costs for a potentially life changing experience for a young entrepreneur. If you want to contact the organizers, reach out to &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/rohith_v&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@rohith_v&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/nitprashant&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@nitprashant&lt;/a&gt; for questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;images/cool-cartoon-7559797.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/cool-cartoon-7559797.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A Lean State Of Mind&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;say-hello&quot;&gt;Say Hello&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are attending LSM this month, give me a shout &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitortat/twitortat&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt; and say hi. It’d be great to get a few conversations started ahead of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;slides&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/35319264?rel=0&quot; width=&quot;512&quot; height=&quot;421&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px 1px 0; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;     &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/why-im-a-mentor-at-lean-startup-machine-bangalore.html&quot;&gt;Why I'm a Mentor at Lean Startup Machine Bangalore&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 19, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kicking off Levitum Knot Hangouts On Air]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/kicking-off-the-levitum-knot-hangouts-on-air.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/kicking-off-the-levitum-knot-hangouts-on-air</id>
  <updated>2014-05-15 12:42:52 UTCT00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’d blogged recently about how we’ve adopted a &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/running-efficient-meetings-at-your-startup.html&quot;&gt;new approach&lt;/a&gt; to how we’re running meetings at Levitum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/meeting.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A simpler, clear schedule for our meetings&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about how why we’d scheduled our meetings this way, I’d encourage you to read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/running-efficient-meetings-at-your-startup.html&quot;&gt;original post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-knowledge-sharing---the-knot&quot;&gt;Open Knowledge Sharing - The Knot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve begun to host the &lt;code&gt;Knot&lt;/code&gt; on Thursday mornings at 9AM IST | 8:30PM PDT. One of the things that has always amazed me about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.levitum.com&quot;&gt;Levitum&lt;/a&gt; team is the amount of &lt;em&gt;talent and knowledge&lt;/em&gt; everyone has on a wide range of subjects. Often enough, the day to day routine of our work doesn’t let us explore this as much as we’d like. And what better way to bring a team together than just share your knowledge and passion with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And what better way to bring a team together than just share your knowledge and passion with each other.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to cover off a wide range of topics - technology, business, social media, sports, photography, music and more. The goal of these sessions is to keep things &lt;em&gt;informal&lt;/em&gt;, and not need a lot of prep. The topics are also &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; related directly to our business or products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/vpGSdOKSzEo?rel=0&amp;amp;modestbranding=1&amp;amp;autohide=1&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;controls=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The First Knot Edition: A Primer on Photography by Vishnu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first Knot this morning was hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/vishnuratheesh&quot;&gt;Vishnu&lt;/a&gt;, who did an amazing job of priming us on photography. In a little over a half hour, he provided an introduction to the key concepts behind &lt;code&gt;aperture&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;shutter speed&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;ISO&lt;/code&gt;. He also covered &lt;code&gt;depth of field&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;framing&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;composition&lt;/code&gt;, and a number of simple tips that apply to camera phones as well. I’m inspired enough to go out and pick up a &lt;code&gt;DSLR&lt;/code&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of sharing this with everyone else who are interested, we plan open this out to the public. So, if you don’t mind ad-hoc learning without a set agenda or formal structure, join us on our &lt;em&gt;weekly&lt;/em&gt; Knot Hangout on-air. Or, just come hang out and say hello!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knots happen every Thursday, at 9AM IST | 8:30PM PDT&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll post updates on upcoming Knots on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/1/103997295567093285121/posts&quot;&gt;Google Plus page&lt;/a&gt; and on our &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/levitum&quot;&gt;Twitter handle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;guest-speakers---the-friendship-knot&quot;&gt;Guest Speakers - The Friendship Knot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we’d love to do once we’ve started to get a little bit of structure (read: less screw ups) around how we’re running the on air sessions is invite friends at other startups to join us for guest sessions. We’re open to most topic ideas - we’d just like to keep it informative, informal and useful. We think this might be a nice way to brings birds of a feather together, and find others who share common hobbies and passions. If you’d like to be a guest speaker write to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#117;&amp;#109;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#118;&amp;#105;&amp;#116;&amp;#117;&amp;#109;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt; or ping &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/kicking-off-the-levitum-knot-hangouts-on-air.html&quot;&gt;Kicking off Levitum Knot Hangouts On Air&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 15, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running Effective Meetings At Your Startup]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/running-efficient-meetings-at-your-startup.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/running-efficient-meetings-at-your-startup</id>
  <updated>2014-05-04 07:11:59 UTCT00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-grease&quot;&gt;The Grease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-makes-an-effective-meeting&quot;&gt;What makes an effective meeting&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#establish-the-purpose&quot;&gt;Establish the purpose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#invite-less-people&quot;&gt;Invite less people&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#use-the-best-tools&quot;&gt;Use the best tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#keep-conversations-effective&quot;&gt;Keep conversations effective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-we-run-meetings-through-the-week&quot;&gt;How We Run Meetings Through The Week&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#our-schedule&quot;&gt;Our Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#monday---the-sunny-beginning&quot;&gt;Monday - The Sunny Beginning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#tuesday---the-compass&quot;&gt;Tuesday - The Compass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#wednesday---the-caliper&quot;&gt;Wednesday - The Caliper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#thursday---the-knot&quot;&gt;Thursday - The Knot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#friday---the-truth&quot;&gt;Friday - The Truth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.levitum.com&quot;&gt;Levitum&lt;/a&gt;, we are currently experimenting with a clean, new approach to how we’re running meetings during the week. This post shares the thought process behind the changes we’ve made as we’re growing and balancing new priorities. We’re hoping this will help us be more efficient, promote collaboration, and ensure we are looking out for the right things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/meeting.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A simpler, clear schedule for our meetings&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-grease&quot;&gt;The Grease&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While often viewed as a necessary evil in most startups, meetings provide connective communication grease.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meetings. While often viewed as a necessary evil in most startups, they provide connective communication grease. Grease that helps information flow, camaradarie to grow, and keeps your startup running like a well oiled machine. But invariably, too much meetings can be a bad thing. Developers get particularly restless when they end up spending too much time in status meetings. Strategy meetings can often spin into endless self aggrandizing discussions. How do you know when you’ve got the right mix and balance of meetings?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-makes-an-effective-meeting&quot;&gt;What makes an effective meeting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running effective meetings really boils down to three things&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They achieve the meeting’s objective.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They take up a minimum amount of time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They leave participants feeling that a sensible process has been followed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;establish-the-purpose&quot;&gt;Establish the purpose&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also important to decide upon what the key purposes&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; your meetings are for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Communication – share new initiatives, company victories and upcoming challenges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consolidation – unite the team around a common sense of purpose and formally onboard new team members&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confirmation – highlight employee accomplishments which reinforce the company’s values and culture&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motivation – excite employees and describe how the company will win, without ignoring reality or attempting to delude them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;invite-less-people&quot;&gt;Invite less people&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invite less people. Or at least as few people as you really need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The honest truth about this is, we invite too many people all the time. And we attend several meetings where don’t add much value. If you’ve got people who sit through your meetings &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; offering any new perspective or ideas, their attendance was likely optional in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’ve got people who sit through your meetings &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; offering any new perspective or ideas, their attendance was likely optional in the first place.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t doubt that they may have required the context and thought process behind the discussion. But, that may have been better served by providing them a separate 10 minute summary instead of having them sit through an hour long meeting. And this is not about who is smart or who is not - everyone’s got a role to play and a job to get done at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-the-best-tools&quot;&gt;Use the best tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/slack.png&quot; alt=&quot;images/slack.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the context of meetings, it’s important to also cover off collaboration tools. I’ve written about &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/ten-collaboration-tools-every-tech-startup-should-consider.html&quot;&gt;collaboration tools every startup should consider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I’ll  call out some of the newer ones that are arrived since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you may be able to get by with with Skype or other similar general consumer chat apps, most startups I know are using either Campfire, Hipchat or Slack. In our case, we’ve made Slack the primary. I’ve literally gone through weeks without having had to have exchanged emails with my colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tools are particularly effective for distributed teams (we’re in 3 different cities), and help keep everyone on the same page. A quick live conversation is just a click away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-conversations-effective&quot;&gt;Keep conversations effective&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s a few tips from Sean Blanda&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; on keeping the conversations as useful as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There is no judging in brainstorming. Focus on capturing ideas before filtering and critiquing them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring solutions, not problems. Solutioning in the middle of a meeting wastes precious communication time. If you can’t bring proposed solutions to the table, save it for next time or bring it up in private conversations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Review “homework” from the last meeting. Not only does it remind participants what happened last week, it holds attendees accountable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-we-run-meetings-through-the-week&quot;&gt;How We Run Meetings Through The Week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier, we used to mostly operate off a daily standup at 9AM. This used to mostly work ok - we’d just follow up and set up breakout meetings as and when needed. But increasingly, the meetings used to stretch out for an hour or so, often meandering through updates and discussions that weren’t always relevant. Plus, there were certain topics that we ought to have been covering off that simply weren’t surfacing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re trying out a new meeting structure for the week. Every day, the meetings start at 9AM over Google Hangout, and run for half hour to an hour. There are also other meetings not listed here for breakout discussions on technical or marketing activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-schedule&quot;&gt;Our Schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/meeting.png&quot; alt=&quot;/images/meeting.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monday---the-sunny-beginning&quot;&gt;Monday - The Sunny Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/sunflowers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;images/sunflowers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discuss how last week went (brief)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discuss plan for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective of this meeting is to lay out the plan for the week ahead. We’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.leankit.com&quot;&gt;LeanKit&lt;/a&gt; extensively, and use it to track everything. We try to get LeanKit up to date coming in to the meeting so that the rough plan is in place and we need to sync up just to ensure we have a shared context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tuesday---the-compass&quot;&gt;Tuesday - The Compass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/compass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;images/compass.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are we headed in the right direction?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a slightly broader discussion about whether we are on track towards the original goal. While we could have considered moving this to a fortnightly or monthly discussion, it’s important enough since we’re learning a lot rapidly. This gives us a weekly checkpoint to consider whether we need to pivot based on our learnings, or whether we are on course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wednesday---the-caliper&quot;&gt;Wednesday - The Caliper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/caliper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;images/caliper.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are some of the things we are doing well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are things we could be doing better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there things we aren’t doing that we should be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re focused on just 2-3 metrics at this point. They are around acquisition, activation, and retention. In certain areas such as customer development, we currently just track the number of conversations we’ve had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thursday---the-knot&quot;&gt;Thursday - The Knot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/knot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;images/knot.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn a new thing from each other&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that has always amazed me about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.levitum.com&quot;&gt;Levitum&lt;/a&gt; team is the amount of talent and knowledge everyone has on a wide range of subjects. Often enough, the day to day routine of our work doesn’t let us explore this as much as we’d like. And what better way to bring a team together than just share your knowledge and passion with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And what better way to bring a team together than just share your knowledge and passion with each other.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to cover off a wide range of topics - technology, business, social media, sports, photography, music and more. The goal of these sessions is to keep things informal, and not need a lot of prep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interest of sharing this with everyone else who are interested, we plan open this out to the public. So, if you don’t mind ad-hoc learning without a set agenda or formal structure, join us on our weekly Knot Hangout on-air*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;friday---the-truth&quot;&gt;Friday - The Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/truth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;images/truth.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What we accomplished this week&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What have we learnt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Demo/Show/Tell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last day of the week is a show and tell, focused on a quick update on what got accomplished during the period and what our learnings were. This would typically include product demos, code walkthroughs, and general show &amp;amp; tell sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are at a startup, how do you structure your meetings? I’d love to hear what you do, and see if we can learn from your experiences. Chime in via the comments, or drop me a note on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mindtools.com/CommSkll/RunningMeetings.htm&quot;&gt;Running Effective Meetings&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/how-to-run-effective-company-meetings-at-your-startup-avoid-a-revivalist-approach-2011-4&quot;&gt;How To Run Effective Company Meetings At Your Startup - Avoid A Revivalist Approach&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/ten-collaboration-tools-every-tech-startup-should-consider.html&quot;&gt;Collaboration Tools Every Startup Should Consider&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://99u.com/articles/7220/how-to-run-your-meetings-like-apple-and-google&quot;&gt;How to run your meetings like Apple and Google&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/running-efficient-meetings-at-your-startup.html&quot;&gt;Running Effective Meetings At Your Startup&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 14, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unending Love, Audrey Hepburn's Favorite Poem by Rabindranath Tagore]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/unending-love-audrey-hepburn-rabindranath-tagore.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/unending-love-audrey-hepburn-rabindranath-tagore</id>
  <published>2014-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#audrey-hepburns-favorite-poem&quot;&gt;Audrey Hepburn’s Favorite Poem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-full-poem&quot;&gt;The Full Poem&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#gregory-peck-reads-unending-love&quot;&gt;Gregory Peck reads Unending Love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#audrey-the-humanitarian&quot;&gt;Audrey the Humanitarian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ma-belle&quot;&gt;Ma Belle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/hepburn.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/hepburn.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/tagore.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/tagore.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Tagore wrote Audrey Hepburn&#39;s favorite poem&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audrey-hepburns-favorite-poem&quot;&gt;Audrey Hepburn’s Favorite Poem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Google celebrates Audrey Hepburn’s&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; birthday with this lovely doodle&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, it’s worth re-reading one of her favorite poems by Rabindranath Tagore &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, Unending Love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a lovely little piece where Tagore subtly immerses the reader in experiences of love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Clad in the light of a pole-star piercing the darkness of time:
You become an image of what is remembered forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are taken back and forth across time, which if you ask me, makes the piece feel even more ethereal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today it is heaped at your feet, it has found its end in you
The love of all man’s days both past and forever:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-full-poem&quot;&gt;The Full Poem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the full poem, translated from the original Bengali by William Radice&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. William was an English poet who spent decades with Tagore, developing a deep understanding of his work, and honed techniques for translation into English which retained the power of the original prose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
Unending Love

I seem to have loved you in numberless forms, numberless times…
In life after life, in age after age, forever.
My spellbound heart has made and remade the necklace of songs,
That you take as a gift, wear round your neck in your many forms,
In life after life, in age after age, forever.

Whenever I hear old chronicles of love, its age-old pain,
Its ancient tale of being apart or together.
As I stare on and on into the past, in the end you emerge,
Clad in the light of a pole-star piercing the darkness of time:
You become an image of what is remembered forever.

You and I have floated here on the stream that brings from the fount.
At the heart of time, love of one for another.
We have played along side millions of lovers, shared in the same
Shy sweetness of meeting, the same distressful tears of farewell-
Old love but in shapes that renew and renew forever.

Today it is heaped at your feet, it has found its end in you
The love of all man’s days both past and forever:
Universal joy, universal sorrow, universal life.
The memories of all loves merging with this one love of ours –
And the songs of every poet past and forever.

- Rabindranath Tagore

&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gregory-peck-reads-unending-love&quot;&gt;Gregory Peck reads Unending Love&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/DL_yVhwxCSY?hd=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;autohide=1&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;After Audrey&#39;s death, Gregory Peck reads out her favorite poems.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;audrey-the-humanitarian&quot;&gt;Audrey the Humanitarian&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“As you grow older, you will discover that you have two hands, one for helping yourself, the other for helping others.”
- Audrey Hepburn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/audrey-2hands.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;images/audrey-2hands.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ma-belle&quot;&gt;Ma Belle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a more personal note, I’ll always remember this day since it’s also my &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt;, my constant companion, Ma Belle’s birthday. She turns six today! And in so many ways, she is Hepburn-eque, with all the grace, poise, and regal bearing that that Audrey was much loved for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ma_belle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;/images/ma_belle.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audrey_Hepburn&quot;&gt;Audrey Hepburn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mirror.co.uk/news/world-news/audrey-hepburn-google-celebrates-hollywood-3493881&quot;&gt;Google’s Doodle for Audrey Hepburn&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rabindranath_Tagore&quot;&gt;Rabindranath Tagore&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/author/list/96721.William_Radice&quot;&gt;William Radice&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/unending-love-audrey-hepburn-rabindranath-tagore.html&quot;&gt;Unending Love, Audrey Hepburn's Favorite Poem by Rabindranath Tagore&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on May 04, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Checklist of Lean Startup Customer Development Interview Questions]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/lean-startup-customer-development-interviews.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/lean-startup-customer-development-interviews</id>
  <published>2014-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
	&lt;header&gt;
		&lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#personas-and-segmentation&quot;&gt;Personas and Segmentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#open-discovery&quot;&gt;Open Discovery&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#probe&quot;&gt;Probe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#quantify&quot;&gt;Quantify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#jumping-into-validation&quot;&gt;Jumping Into Validation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#closure&quot;&gt;Closure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pitfalls--tips&quot;&gt;Pitfalls &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#using-turk&quot;&gt;Using Turk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#disruption&quot;&gt;Disruption&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Read the follow on post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/why-lean-startup-is-hard-in-practice.html&quot;&gt;Why Lean Startup Is Hard In Practice&lt;/a&gt;, that’s part of an ongoing series on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp.html&quot;&gt;recent post&lt;/a&gt;, I covered off learnings from an MVP we built out for charades online&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The post was quite popular, and made it to page one of Hacker News and Reddit, bringing in over 25,000 hits in a week. I learnt tons from comments and feedback from people, and also got to know a number of amazing people around the world like &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/skmurphy&quot;&gt;@skmurphy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/trikro&quot;&gt;@trikro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/spikelab&quot;&gt;@spikelabs&lt;/a&gt; who are applying lean to their ventures. Closer to home, I had great conversations with &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mtrajan&quot;&gt;@mtrajan&lt;/a&gt; and others that are a part of the local lean startup circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that there were certain things that came naturally to me, but are areas which some people tend to get stuck at. I’m going to expand on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp.html&quot;&gt;original post&lt;/a&gt; to dive into a few of them in the interest of sharing and continuing to &lt;a href=&quot;http://steveblank.com/2011/09/15/the-pay-it-forward-culture/&quot;&gt;learn from each other&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one question a number of people asked me via &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7578518&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;, LinkedIn and Disqus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How do you go about interviewing people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s multiple dimensions to that question, and I’ll attempt to answer only part in this post. And that is,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What are some of the typical questions you ask during a customer interview?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve put together a list of common questions that I’ve been asking people I interview. Note that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These questions are mostly targeted towards an enterprise/SaaS B2B or B2B2C type of discovery.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also, I’m not laying out a complete script for you to follow - these are just the &lt;em&gt;important&lt;/em&gt; questions that you may want to cover off.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m not discussing how you may acquire these users, although I’ll share some tips further down in the article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/niche.png&quot; alt=&quot;/images/niche.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personas-and-segmentation&quot;&gt;Personas and Segmentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective here is to get a general introduction to the person and see if they matches up against the personas or customer segments that we’ve identified. Note that personas and segmentations are not the same&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and you’ll likely care more about personas at this stage. Personas are more representative of &lt;em&gt;behavioral&lt;/em&gt; patterns&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and provides deeper insight into why someone may need your product. You would want to ensure you’ve identified these before you jump into talking to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a possible set of open questions to break the ice and get a conversation started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s a day in your life like?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me about what life is like doing &lt;em&gt;activity&lt;/em&gt; (or working at &lt;em&gt;company&lt;/em&gt;)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How would you describe yourself? (in a few minutes)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-discovery&quot;&gt;Open Discovery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an open ended discussion to discover the persons problems and let them explain it using their own words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the part of your day that you hate the most?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the current tools that you use? What are some of the things that you wish they did?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/custdev.png&quot; alt=&quot;/images/custdev.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;probe&quot;&gt;Probe&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s really only &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; question&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; here that you need to keep asking. Attempt to get to the root of why there is an underlying problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest in saying that this was hard, especially since the conversation can get a bit uncomfortable. I’m trying not to shy away from asking these hard questions, since they ensure I’m not double thinking on behalf of the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quantify&quot;&gt;Quantify&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a sense of how deep the problem is, and size the opportunity &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much of a problem is that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for areas where they express pain, and note the words that they use. It’s particularly useful to use these later in follow on conversations so that you are speaking their language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jumping-into-validation&quot;&gt;Jumping Into Validation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case a problem set that you are particularly interested in didn’t come up in the conversation, you may want to consider just putting it out there and seeing how they respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One example where this approach may be useful is if your product’s unique proposition is based on the experience it offers. These can be hard to approach from a problem/solution fit Q&amp;amp;A if the user is unable to visualize how things could be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, if your idea was a Flipboard style app, it would be hard to explain the unique experience to a Google Reader user. In this case, a mockup (or even a working prototype) may be needed to assist with your interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What do you think about this product “insert the value proposition”?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you be ready to use this immediately?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you be ready to pay $x per month for this product?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we didn’t build this product (or it didn’t exist), how disappointed would you be? Ask the respondee to choose between
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Very Disappointed&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Somewhat Disappointed&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Slightly Disappointed&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Don’t Care.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;closure&quot;&gt;Closure&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on summarizing the key points that you have noted, and give them time to correct things that you may not have heard right. Seek referrals of others who have the same problem that you can talk to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you mind referring me to others in your network who may have the same problem?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One idea that I have but haven’t explored yet, is to see if I can get some of the early adopters to publicly endorse your idea someplace where this can help you around when you launch. For instance, a scheduled tweet or post at launch time to help you build momentum. This might be more relevant for mobile apps where a big bang launch still pays off with app store rankings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;pitfalls--tips&quot;&gt;Pitfalls &amp;amp; Tips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One of the challenges I’ve faced so far has been that it’s not easy when there are certain barriers to reaching your target users. I’ve made the mistake of talking to what we thought were reasonable approximations (users of the same age group, but in a different part of the world). &lt;em&gt;They were not representative&lt;/em&gt;.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There’s the story of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/asmartbear/&quot;&gt;Jason Cohen&lt;/a&gt; of WPEngine. During their early days, Jason got onto LinkedIn and wrote a number of bloggers directly. To show that he really valued their time, he offered to pay for their time during the interviews. He spoke to several people until he found 30 that were willing to pay $49/mo for a hosted wordpress service. If you are comfortable side stepping any personal reservations and reaching out to people, you may find that doors open.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also, no amount of secondary research online can compensate since you are ultimately extrapolating based on what you’ve infered from someone elses high level summary. Earlier on, I’ve spent hours looking at well laid out reports aggregating data from sites online since I would hesitate to reach out and talk to users. Don’t ever assume you can substitute one for the other - &lt;em&gt;both are valuable in their own ways&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are periods when you may feel like you are learning nothing from the conversations you are having. Persist, and take time later to go back and listen to your recordings or review your notes. &lt;em&gt;The dots will start to line up&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-turk&quot;&gt;Using Turk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I was asked recently if we’d considered using Amazon’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mturk.com/mturk/welcome&quot;&gt;Mechanical Turk&lt;/a&gt; for B2C interviews. Well, we hadn’t. One part of the challenge was that I don’t think my thought process on the interview structure had matured enough to whittle it down to a list I could easily pass on to someone to follow. The other part to be honest was that I felt that I’d want to probe more to really explore and discover, and that would be hard to pass on via Turk. In many ways, this was so core to my understanding of the users that it wouldnt be something I would outsource away. I suspect that in the future, I might use Turk &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; I’ve spoken to a sizeable sampling of people as a means of validating that my initial sampling size wasnt too small.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;disruption&quot;&gt;Disruption&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s one other question I’ve gotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What if I have a great disruptive idea, but it’s not something users may be able to imagine at this point?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IMHO, if you’re attempting to do something truly disruptive, it’s quite likely that most people arent going to be able to understand what your vision is. It’s also quite likely that you may not be able to fully explain it either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that case, I’m not totally sure this customer development approach may help you with broader questions that you seek answers too. But then I also hope that you’ve got enough VC money to help you chase down a problem which isnt totally straightforward - you’re likely looking at a fairly longer term play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;We’re still learning and would love to hear how you go about this. What are the common questions you ask? Feel free to share your tips in the comments below, or send me a message &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Also, you may want to read the follow on post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/running-efficient-meetings-at-your-startup.html&quot;&gt;how we’re improving how we run our meetings effectively at our startup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp.html&quot;&gt;What We Learnt From A Failed MVP&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foolproof.co.uk/insight/blog/why-market-segmentation-is-not-the-same-as-personas/&quot;&gt;Why Market Segmentation Is Not The Same As Personas&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2001/08/perfecting_your_personas.html&quot;&gt;Perfecting Your Personas&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/5_Whys&quot;&gt;The 5 Whys&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ecorner.stanford.edu/authorMaterialInfo.html?mid=2058&quot;&gt;The Customer Development Process&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/lean-startup-customer-development-interviews.html&quot;&gt;A Checklist of Lean Startup Customer Development Interview Questions&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on April 29, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seth Godin on Not Reinventing the Wheel]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/seth-on-not-reinventing-the-wheel.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/seth-on-not-reinventing-the-wheel</id>
  <published>2014-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/seth-godin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;/images/seth-godin.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Steal your business model. We don’t have a shortage of business models, it’s okay if you pick one that’s already working for someone else.
When it comes down to the thing you will be known for, your uniqueness, your gift, your thing worth talking about–don’t steal that.
For the rest, honor those that came before and use their work as a building block for yours.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A succinct gem by Seth Godin on why it’s time we stopped reinventing the wheel. &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2014/04/steal-dont-invent.html&quot;&gt;See original article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/seth-on-not-reinventing-the-wheel.html&quot;&gt;Seth Godin on Not Reinventing the Wheel&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on April 20, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Lost Ten Kilos In A Year]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/how-i-lost-ten-kilos-in-a-year.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/how-i-lost-ten-kilos-in-a-year</id>
  <updated>2014-04-15T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#then-and-now&quot;&gt;Then and Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#why-you-should-read-this&quot;&gt;Why you should read this&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ah-food&quot;&gt;Ah, Food!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#my-exercise-routine&quot;&gt;My exercise routine.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#food-intake&quot;&gt;Food Intake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-hockey-stick-effect&quot;&gt;The Hockey Stick Effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#slowing-down&quot;&gt;Slowing Down&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-typical-day&quot;&gt;A Typical Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#losing-10-kilos&quot;&gt;Losing 10 Kilos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#when-things-went-wrong&quot;&gt;When Things Went Wrong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#happiness&quot;&gt;Happiness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;then-and-now&quot;&gt;Then and Now&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a decade back, when I lived in Menlo Park, California, I weighed 84 kg (185 pounds). That’s not as light as I’d ever been soon after my scrawny teenage years, but it’s as close to be being lean and fit as I can recall. Back then, I used to play tennis regularly, and frequently ran 10 and 20K road races. I used to bike to work in Redwood City and back daily (22 miles), and then down to Palo Alto for my classes (7 miles).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But about the same time last year, I tipped the scales at 95 kg (210 pounds). Now, that wouldn’t be so bad if I was a muscular giant, but I’m relatively lean. I’d accumulated the &lt;em&gt;signs of prosperity&lt;/em&gt; (as a friend called it) over time, no thanks to a sedentary lifestyle, and a love for gluttony. At one point, one of our colleagues used to chide us that consuming large amounts of food was becoming one of our core competencies! Plus, my flexibility had gone down significantly, which was also making me more injury prone during recreational play. Twice, after playing a couple of hours of tennis, I ended up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plantar_fasciitis&quot;&gt;plantar fasciitis&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a painful injury to the arch of the foot, and the only way to recover was to walk as little as possible. The added weight didn’t help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-you-should-read-this&quot;&gt;Why you should read this&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is the story of how I lost 10 kilos in a year. And I did this without following new fangled diets, hiring a fitness instructor, using apps or gadgets to help track things, or doing anything else unnatural. Along the way, I encountered a little setback which I wasn’t expecting. I’m sharing all of this in the hope this may inspire others to find their own journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary objective in losing weight is to get back to a level of fitness that I’ll be proud of. While I wasn’t proud of the pot belly I’d been carry around, physical appearance and how I’m perceived was not a factor. I consider myself fairly self motivated, and don’t believe I look for external validation to make me feel good. We’re all narcissistic at some level, and I’m not going to try to portray myself as being holier than thou. The point I’m making is, I feel this needs to be about &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; health and &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; well being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ah-food&quot;&gt;Ah, Food!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/remy-ratatouille.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;You get the picture.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other factor that made all of this challenging? I love food. Remember Remy&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from Ratatouille, and those moments of explosions in his mind as he combines different flavors? Well, that’s me. I used to write a popular food blog a while back, and checking off new restaurants that had opened up in the city used to be a weekly routine. I still wanted to enjoy the good life, and eat all the things I love. And not have to starve myself or live on salads on boiled vegetables just in order to tilt the scales a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the first part of the journey was a combination of discipline and routine coupled with experimentation. I tried to organize my week so that I’d get at least an hour daily. This meant an hour of either tennis or swimming every morning soon after I got up. On weekend, I’d push this a bit harder, and get about two hours in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;Sure, this sounds simple, the hard part was doing this &lt;em&gt;daily&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-exercise-routine&quot;&gt;My exercise routine.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Train insane. Or remain the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday through Friday&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:00 AM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; An hour long game of tennis, or a 45 minute swim in the pool.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8:00 AM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; An 1 km walk with the dog.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weekends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 AM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; A two hour long game of tennis.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8:30 AM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; Pull ups, stretches, core exercises at the gym.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9:00 AM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; An 1 km walk with the dog.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;food-intake&quot;&gt;Food Intake&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part was food intake. I continued to eat the same things that I used to, but reduced the quantity I was consuming gradually. I stopped eating from a plate, and instead started to use a bowl. Psychologically, it helped me focus on capping my consumption instead of just loading up a plate or going back for another little helping. I spaced out my meals well, and started to have a larger breakfast and a smaller dinner. I continued to eat out, but I’d pass on greasy buffets and pick smaller a la carte plates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hockey-stick-effect&quot;&gt;The Hockey Stick Effect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third part was getting into a rhythm. During the first few weeks, it was particularly important to steady the food intake. Initially, my weight loss was neutralized by the muscle I was adding, causing my weight to increase just a bit. I continued to persevere, and saw a marked hockey stick effect with my weight starting to drop soon after. I tried not to be too worried about a  daily or weekly goal, but to be overall comfortable with a steady rate of weight loss. One other thing I did was to ensure I was supplementing with diet with a wholesome mix of fruits, veggies, pulses and dairy products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;slowing-down&quot;&gt;Slowing Down&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was soon losing about a kilo a month, and this was a steady comfortable pace. I’d gotten my weight down to just below 90kg, and I was starting to feel I was cruising. I was wrong. There was one point where I tried to push it a bit too hard, and I remember when I &lt;em&gt;realized&lt;/em&gt; it. I used to get quite tired by the end of the day, at times needing 8 full hours of sleep. There was one time I remember feeling just a little giddy one afternoon and having to stop at Maiya’s and get a snack. It was my body &lt;em&gt;screaming at me to slow down&lt;/em&gt;. And I stopped, and just listened. I slightly increased my intake, even if that meant slower progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I’d gotten to 89 kg, progress was painfully slow. Every 100 grams on the scale was hard fought. My body was now lean, toned, and I was feeling more active and sprightly than before. I’d gotten into a daily rhythm of exercise. I was disciplined about food intake, and things were far more predictable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-typical-day&quot;&gt;A Typical Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s sort of what a typical day looked like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:00 AM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; 1 Tall glass of milk, and half an apple.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9:00 AM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; 2-3 slices of toast, a little cheese, and a kullad of black tea.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; A small bowl of brown rice, lots of dal, lots of veggies. Once a week, I’d have grilled or pan fried fish.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; A little snack. Chocolate. Biscuits. Ice cream. It didn’t matter what it was, but it had to be a small quantity.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; A small bowl of brown rice, lots of dal, lots of veggies.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10:30 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; Half an apple.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t really research this online, or consult a dietician, although I’ll recommend that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; consider doing so. I largely went with a mix of what well right, and I felt my body was responding well to. I never stopped occasionally eating other things I enjoyed - red meat, drinking wine or beer, and even greasy masala dosas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that didn’t help with the weight loss was little vacations in Goa and Kerala in between. It made no sense to not indulge in the generous of helpings of lobster, calamari, crab and sea fish that I love, and I came back about a kilo heavier each time. But I came back happier, with the weight of the past and the future discarded, living in the moment. And in the longer, bigger scheme of things, that’s &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; what matters, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;losing-10-kilos&quot;&gt;Losing 10 Kilos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I was at 87kg, and I felt things were plateauing a bit, I started to add a quick daily run to the mix. I’ve always taken my dog for a daily 1 km walk in the mornings either before or after other workouts. But that’s always been a leisurely half hour stroll while Ma Belle takes her time doing her thing. Once I was done walking her, I started to get back out for a quick 1 km run. Gradually, I built up pace until I was doing sub 5 minute runs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/weight_20140322.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I did it! 95 to 85 in one year.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, I hit 85. The magic number. I’d lost ten kilos in a year, and I’d made it with great &lt;em&gt;determination&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;discipline&lt;/em&gt;. I didn’t realize it then, but my joy was short lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-things-went-wrong&quot;&gt;When Things Went Wrong&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was one weekend where I pushed too hard again. I played tennis one morning, then went for a swim, and then hit the courts again in the evening for another game. While we were still warming up, I felt pain in the lower knee, just below the knee cap. At first I sat down, hoping it was just cramps. But the pain didn’t ease out. A trip to Manipal Hospital the next day, several tests later, and after hours waiting at their ortho, I was told that the meniscus and cartilage in my knee were likely wearing out. The ortho also said that I would likely be unable to engage in rigourous exercise much again. &lt;em&gt;I felt gutted&lt;/em&gt;. I’d always hoped to be able to continue playing tennis and swimming for as long as I could. And for that moment, I was reminded of the frailty of life, and how quickly things can change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, my neighbours referred to me to Dr Praveen Kumar, an ortho in Koramangala. Praveen advised me to take an MRI immediately, and then I went back that evening for the results. As I sat in the ortho’s waiting area, I pondered whether this would mean I’d finally need to stop making fun of my buddies who are golf regulars and start hitting the range. When I was called in, Praveen quietly went through all the scan results. He gave me a clean chit! There were no issues with the meniscus or cartilage, or anything cause of longer term concern. I’d torn soft tissue under the knee, but that should heal fully in a month. I was so relieved, I could have hugged him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;happiness&quot;&gt;Happiness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Obsession is a young man’s game. My only excuse is that I never grew old.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Michael Caine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started off on this little journey since I wasn’t happy with how things were. My weight might not stick around at 85. However, I’ll likely do my best to keep it around there with a continued balance of exercise and eating well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m goal oriented and disciplined about how I go about trying to achieve it. But at times, it’s easy to obsess and go overboard. I did, and I got lucky that I didn’t cause any longer term damage to my knee. Nadal may have a battery of medics to help him get by, but you and I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve sworn to go easy on high impact exercises in the future, and mix it up with a lot more of regular swimming. It’s easy to let your goals go out of hand and let you obsess more than you need to. And that in the end ends up being detrimental to your original goals. And thereby, in the way of happiness you initially craved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;So, stay &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; to your goals. But don’t let &lt;em&gt;happiness&lt;/em&gt; get out of sight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Image courtesy Disney/Pixar, from the motion picture Ratatouille. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/how-i-lost-ten-kilos-in-a-year.html&quot;&gt;How I Lost Ten Kilos In A Year&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on April 15, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What We Learnt From A Failed MVP (Lean Startup)]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp</id>
  <updated>2014-04-14T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#initial-vision&quot;&gt;Initial Vision&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-big-ifs&quot;&gt;The Big IFs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hypothesis-1&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hypothesis-2&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hypothesis-3&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hypothesis-4&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#hypothesis-5&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-conundrum&quot;&gt;The Conundrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-we-did-well&quot;&gt;What we did well&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what-we-could-have-done-better&quot;&gt;What we could have done better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#was-this-a-failed-mvp&quot;&gt;Was this a ‘failed’ MVP?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-decision&quot;&gt;The Decision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Read the follow on post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/lean-startup-customer-development-interviews.html&quot;&gt;lean startup customer development interview questions&lt;/a&gt;, that’s part of an ongoing series on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fastcompany.com/1826976/dirty-little-secret-overnight-successes&quot;&gt;Rovio tried 51 games before hitting upon Angry Birds&lt;/a&gt;. We tend to hear a lot more about the chart busting numbers of Angry Birds than the struggles of the previous 51 games. In my opinion, their success was the &lt;em&gt;journey&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;52&lt;/em&gt; experiments, and &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; just the final one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.levitum.com&quot;&gt;Levitum&lt;/a&gt; recently had learnings from an MVP that we put out, and experiments that we ran. In the spirit of openly sharing how I’ve tried to apply Lean Startup principles to a new venture, I’m going to outline how we went about things, and what I’ve learnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-vision&quot;&gt;Initial Vision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the initial vision, target audience, and problem statement that we started off with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VISION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;A fun place where people make new friends online.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;TARGET&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Teens, College kids, Yuppies, Casual gamers.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;PROBLEM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Connecting people online through dumb charades.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we thought about this, there were a number of questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do people care at all about Charades? It turned out that Ellen’s charades game was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bf8RTdWdd44&quot;&gt;wildly popular&lt;/a&gt;, and there was a lot of buzz around Heads Up Charades, but that was not indicative about whether people would want to play online.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would charades be engaging enough that people would want to play regularly?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we set up a real-time game to mimic the mechanics of the game we are used to, that would require friends being present at the same time, which may be hard to schedule.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If scheduling was hard, would people be comfortable playing with strangers in games rooms like poker online.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wouldn’t people freak out just a bit about turning video online? Are there communities that are more open to video online?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we built an async game with mobile apps so that people could play when they had time, that might work. But would it be practical for people to respond to a challenge by acting holding their smartphones in front of them?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And then, there was the question of whether we had an interest and competencies in gaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-big-ifs&quot;&gt;The Big IFs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set out to break these down and tackle what we felt were the biggest &lt;em&gt;ifs&lt;/em&gt; on our list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If&lt;/em&gt; people are interested in playing charades online, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; they are comfortable turning on video, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; they like the concept enough to invite friends or join a public game room, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; they enjoy the playing experience with others in the room, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; they enjoy this enough to keep coming back, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; they will invite other people,
we had a shot at something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we attempted to structure experiments around the major leap of faith assumptions being made, in order to seek validation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hypothesis-1&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Of a sampling set of people searching for Charades online, at least 25% will sign up to check out the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AUDIENCE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;People looking to play charades online.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ACQUISITION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google Ads.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VALIDATION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;% of signups.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;EXECUTION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1. Build signup page in a day.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2. Identify keywords, run ads for a week&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3. Track signups&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RESULT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;We ran ads targeting users who searched for ‘charades online’, ‘charades games’, and ‘charades words’. Over 25% of the users signed up.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;LEARNING&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;There’s a interest in playing charades online amongst those who google for it.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/fwc-wf-2.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Initial signup wireframe.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hypothesis-2&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Of users in the target demographic who are shown mocked up up flows of the game concept, at least 70% of them would be very interested in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AUDIENCE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Young Adults in India&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ACQUISITION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Friends Network&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VALIDATION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;% of people who are very interested in the game.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;EXECUTION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1. Build rough mockups using MockFlow in a day.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2. Walk people through the mockups&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3. Collect feedback.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RESULT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Overall, there unanimous interest in the game concept. A few mentioned that they may be uncomfortable being on video online.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;LEARNING&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;In general, charades is popular in India, and people are interested in trying out an online game.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/fwc-wf.png&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Two screen from the initial wireframes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hypothesis-3&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Of signed up Charades users invited to a game room, at least 25% will be willing to join a public room and turn video on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AUDIENCE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Signed up users&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ACQUISITION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;N/A&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VALIDATION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;% of users who turn on video in a public room.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;EXECUTION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1. Invite users to the public room&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2. Provide an explanation about what the game is about.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3. Enable the user to turn video on and start the game.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4. Track analytics.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RESULT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;80% of the users visited the page, but &amp;lt; 5% turned video on.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;LEARNING&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;This experiment invalidated our false hope that people in this era of Facetime and Hangouts wouldn’t hesitate to turn video on. We needed to dig deeper, and talk to users to understand what they felt.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hypothesis-4&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Users are more likely to be comfortable turning on video if they are playing with their friends, and 80% or more will turn video on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AUDIENCE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Friends of Friends who are acquainted with each other, but don’t know each other well.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ACQUISITION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Friends Network&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VALIDATION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;% of users who turn on video on.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;% of users who like the game idea enough that they would be disappointed to not play.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;EXECUTION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1. Invite users to the public room&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2. Provide an explanation about what the game is about.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3. Enable the user to turn video on and start the game.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4. Track analytics.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RESULT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;100% of the users turned video on, and were excited and ready to engage in the game. They felt they would be very disappointed if they were unable to play.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;LEARNING&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Women in the group, when asked if they would play with people they didn’t know online, said they would hesitate. Men in the group unanimously said they would be willing to try.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hypothesis-5&quot;&gt;Hypothesis 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Users from online communities that use video a lot with strangers are likely to be comfortable playing with each other, and at least 25% will turn video on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;AUDIENCE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Chatroulette and Chatrandom communities.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;ACQUISITION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Google Ads&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;VALIDATION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;% of users who turn on video on.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;EXECUTION&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1. Run Google Ads for ‘chatroulette’ and ‘chatrandom’, offering video based charades online, and an opportunity to meet new people.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2. Invite users to the public room&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3. Provide an explanation about what the game is about.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4. Enable the user to turn video on and start the game.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5. Track analytics.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6. Added a Qualroo style prompt to find out why they don’t turn video on.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;RESULT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;50% of the users visited the page, but &amp;lt; 10% turned video on. 5% answered the prompt indicating they didn’t want to turn video on, would try later, or weren’t sure how to turn it on.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;LEARNING&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Given the anonymity of these communities, it was hard to reach out directly and get feedback. The sampling size of the responders to the prompt was too small to infer enough.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-conundrum&quot;&gt;The Conundrum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also spoke to a group of users and collated feedback. So, at this point, we were faced with this conundrum from our learnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s a certain level of interest in charades, but it’s mostly seen as a family &amp;amp; friends game.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For those who see their friends &amp;amp; family often enough, playing charades online wasn’t appealing. (Playing live with them during Thanksgiving or Christmas was still appealing).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The average users isn’t comfortable playing with random strangers online.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even communities that are comfortable dealing with nudity online, and have no reservations didn’t find the idea appealing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improvements in the visual design and explanatory information offered did not increase conversions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A game like this requires a fairly engaged community, and it didn’t appear that charades would sustain that level of engagement.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s a community of people in the subcontinent that loves dumb charades, but the version that’s played is fairly technical and geeky, and would not scale out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-did-well&quot;&gt;What we did well&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Capture our thought process and assumptions, laying out things that had to be true for us to succeed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identified small batches that could be proven (or disproven) with minimum cost, rapidly built and iterated through the batches.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stayed honest and objective, tracked metrics and cohorts well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-could-have-done-better&quot;&gt;What we could have done better&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most early feedback was from subcontinent users, since reaching out the an international audience was not easy. However, these were not fully representative of the target audience.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We built more than we should have before we understood the gaps in our understanding of the customer and their behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Included more inline surveys early on enough to have better insights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;was-this-a-failed-mvp&quot;&gt;Was this a ‘failed’ MVP?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An MVP is an experiment or a tool to help answer a high risk question. From that perspective, we would have have failed if we had learnt nothing from our experiments. I’d like to think that we succeeded in learning a lot, and that made this MVP successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, one thing I noticed after I moved back to India from the Valley was that we often hesitate to talk about failures, and what we learnt from them. People are much more interested in learning from a success story. However, if you ask me, I’m more interested in the 51 attempts of Rovio than just the one that made it big. It’s the failure to learn that’s a failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-decision&quot;&gt;The Decision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we still believe in the original vision, and it’s possible that persevering and keep this going out there in the wild may yield something, we’ve decided to put this on hold. Although this is neither a hardcore game or a heavy social game, it requires gaming chops that we don’t have. Our competencies lie in mobile + social and we’re sticking to those. However, the learnings have been useful, and have helped up develop more structure around how we approach customer development, gain early feedback, and rapidly iterate to test out key assumptions. It’s more important that we develop a method that will help us get predictable around how we solve customer problems than getting lucky. I’m sure these will help us as we move on to the next stepping stones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FEEDBACK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Are there things that you think we could have done differently? Chime in via the comments. This article made it to the first page on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=7578518&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Also, you may want to read the follow on post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/lean-startup-customer-development-interviews.html&quot;&gt;lean startup customer development interview questions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/what-we-learnt-from-a-failed-mvp.html&quot;&gt;What We Learnt From A Failed MVP (Lean Startup)&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on April 11, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five Most Popular Amul Ads Of 2013]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/five-most-popular-amul-ads-of-2013.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/five-most-popular-amul-ads-of-2013</id>
  <published>2014-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wonder what the most popular Amul Ads of 2013 were?  Well, here’s a quick round up of the top 5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/amul_stats.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Record number of users of the Amul App in 2013&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These stats were collated from users of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/amulios/&quot;&gt;Amul Cartoon Ads Mobile App&lt;/a&gt;, which can be downloaded for iOS &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/amul-cartoon-ads/id363119867&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you’d like to contribute towards building the Android app, give me a shout in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;Quiz Time! Guess what each ads is about in the comments. Answers will be updated shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sir-aankhon-par&quot;&gt;5. “Sir… aankhon par!”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/amul5.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aa-balle-mujhe-maar&quot;&gt;4. “Aa Balle Mujhe Maar!”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/amul4.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;patekar-says-na-na-to-baba&quot;&gt;3. “Patekar Says Na-Na to Baba!”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/amul3.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;x-ten-dulkar&quot;&gt;2. “4 x Ten dulkar!”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/amul2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gayle-khel-mein&quot;&gt;1. “Gayle Khel Mein!”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/amul1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;Quiz Time! Guess what each ads is about in the comments. Answers will be updated shortly.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/five-most-popular-amul-ads-of-2013.html&quot;&gt;Five Most Popular Amul Ads Of 2013&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on April 09, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Applying Lean Startup Principles To Mobile App Development]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/applying-lean-startup-principles-to-mobile-app-development.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/applying-lean-startup-principles-to-mobile-app-development</id>
  <updated>2014-04-05T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I attended &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.droidsync.in&quot;&gt;DroidSync&lt;/a&gt;, an event organized in Mumbai by my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/prajyotm&quot;&gt;Prajyot Mainkar&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.androcid.com&quot;&gt;Androcid&lt;/a&gt; for app developers and entrepreneurs. I presented a session in the Business Track about applying Lean Startup principles to Mobile App Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read on for a quick abstract, and my slides futher below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-new-app-idea-is-one-in-a-million&quot;&gt;Your New App Idea is One in a Million&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve got this great new idea, but your idea literally is one in a million. There’s a million other apps on the iTunes and Play Store, and over a billion downloads. 99% of the apps are downloaded &amp;lt; 1000 times, and are launched just once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put another way, those numbers no longer have any meaning. It’s a massive junk pile of apps that solve problems no one has, or ever will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last three years that I’ve been the Program Chair for Droidcon, I’ve noticed this pattern repeat itself with a number of app developers. We’d rather spend hours polishing our app icon than talking to real users to ensure that we are really addressing a problem they have. There’s certainly exceptions, and there are a few outstanding app entrepreneurs around. But lets be honest - they are a minority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-the-junk-pile&quot;&gt;Avoid the Junk Pile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can you do to avoid your app ending up in the same trash can? Well, there’s no silver bullet for sure, but my learning has been that applying Lean Startup principles to Mobile App Development can help. These principles provide a structured approach to experimentation, customer development, and learning. They will help you ensure that what you are building is what someone out there &lt;em&gt;really wants&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-a-lean-mobile-startup&quot;&gt;Be a Lean Mobile Startup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My slides also cover off a few tips to work around common objections to applying lean to mobile app dev such as longer dev cycles, the need for a big bang app launch to get higher rankings and wider distribution, and a lack of A/B testing and cohorts analysis tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/35200281&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;auto&quot; id=&quot;iframe1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; onload=&quot;autoResize(&#39;iframe1&#39;);&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got feedback or other ideas about how you’ve applied lean to your app development? Chime in in the comments below. Or, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;Follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; for more updates and discussions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My thanks for inputs &amp;amp; ideas that have contributed to these slides go to: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ashmaurya&quot;&gt;@ashmaurya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/mtrajan&quot;&gt;@mtrajan&lt;/a&gt;, my team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.levitum.in&quot;&gt;Levitum&lt;/a&gt; and various members of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/droidconIN&quot;&gt;@droidconIN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/pncamp&quot;&gt;@pncamp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/blrdroid&quot;&gt;@blrdroid&lt;/a&gt; communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also a big shout out to the other awesome speakers &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/amsanjeev&quot;&gt;Amrit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ravivyas84&quot;&gt;Ravi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/PG1O1&quot;&gt;Prateek&lt;/a&gt;, Garima, Boaz, and Santosh. The highlight of the day for me was the time we spent having an open chat with the audience from the stage. And thanks once again for Androcid for pulling off a great event, and wonderful hospitality. They also organized NitroDroid in Goa, and doing a great job broadening and enabling the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/applying-lean-startup-principles-to-mobile-app-development.html&quot;&gt;Applying Lean Startup Principles To Mobile App Development&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on April 05, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Three Tennis Serve Tips I Wish I Had Known Earlier]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/three-tennis-serve-tips-i-wish-i-had-known-earlier.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/three-tennis-serve-tips-i-wish-i-had-known-earlier</id>
  <published>2014-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2014-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I watch Roger Federer serve, his fluid brilliance is incredibly captivating. Balanced and relaxed start position. Check. Graceful rocking motion. Check. Rapid arm pronation. Check. Explosion at contact. Check. It’s poetry in motion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d watch me serve a year back, my inconsistency was jarring. My toss would floats up to a different place every time, as if carried by a sudden gust of wind. I would move my right foot as if I’m kick starting a motorbike. As my serve would start to falter, I’d start to toss the ball higher and try hitting it harder, as if that would magically start to work some magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s when I discovered set of marvellous YouTube videos that helped me tune my technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My serve isn’t terrific yet, but there’s a marked improvement. I’m more fluid and relaxed. The toss is more consistent. I’m able to consistently get a mix of flat, top spin and slice serves in and mix up the placement for some variety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few things that I learnt along the way that may help you. I’ve consolidated the videos around these learnings to make this a lot easier for you to follow along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-toss-the-ball&quot;&gt;#1. Don’t Toss the Ball&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Counter intuitive as it may seem, one of the main challenges I’d had all along was that I was &lt;em&gt;tossing&lt;/em&gt; the ball in the air. Inadvertently, I was using my wrist or elbow which ended up making the ball move around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/CnMolTSCUqo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Roger in full fluid motion.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key lessons to learn here are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t bend the elbow on the toss&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your wrist relaxed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember that when you release the ball you must &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; impart any additional momentum to it - the ball release is just an extension of the upward movement of your arm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZTg9gpMtAmw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Here&#39;s another one on the toss position for different types of serves.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One great tip that helped me was to switch how I held the ball. Earlier, I used to hold the ball with my finger tips. I struggled with this, since I invariably imparted some momentum or spin with my fingers or wrist. Instead, I switched to a new toss grip which locked my wrist. I started to hold the ball the way I’d hold an ice cream cone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;b-the-ice-cream-cone-release&quot;&gt;#1-b. The Ice Cream Cone Release&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is simple. Relax your wrist, and hold the ball between your curled forefinger and thumb, just like you’d hold an ice cream cone. As your arm extends upwards, the release is a natural extension of the moment. The cone grip avoids adding momentum across the forward/backward axis since your wrist is locked. For an example, watch the video below of Roger Federer tossing the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/r8Ag2PPam5o&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Pop the cone.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relax-your-wrist&quot;&gt;#2. Relax Your Wrist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the other strokes - the forehand, backhand and volleys require that our wrist be firm. And it turns out, there’s a perfectly logical explanation for this. In those cases, the ball is already in motion, and keeping our wrist loose makes it harder for us to control the racquet face at the point of contact. The serve is the one stroke
where the player has total control (well, once you’ve got a handle on the toss) over the ball position at the point of contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relaxing your wrist causes the racquet head to gain additional rotation momentum as it heads towards the point of contact. This rotational momentum is what helps generate slight top spin, which keeps a flat serve inside the court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/EgmNag6Ebyw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Relax your wrist, and unlock the potential of your serve.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait, did I just say a flat serve involves top spin? Yes, I did. The fact is, a tennis player needs to be 7-8 feet tall to hit a &lt;em&gt;flat&lt;/em&gt; serve into the court. All flat serves involve a bit of spin to keep them in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever heard someone ask you to ‘hit down on the ball’? Well, now you know the physics behind what they were asking you to do. They are right in that this is different from a top spin serve (more on that later), but there’s a certain amount of spin needed to work the magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that, my friend, is one of the little implicit secrets of the serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-hit-through-the-ball---throw-your-racquet-at-it&quot;&gt;#3. Don’t Hit Through The Ball - Throw Your Racquet At It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d heard this several times before, but I just found it really hard to execute. For the longest time, I’d swing at the ball the same way I would with my forehand or backhand. The racquet face would be open so that I could ensure that I middled the ball in the sweet spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a hard learning for many of us to accept. It’s that we tend to over think many of these things. So I’ll need you to just suspect any analysis in your mind and just hear out what I’ll advice on next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quit trying to hit &lt;em&gt;through&lt;/em&gt; the ball.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Throw your racquet at the ball, just like you are throwing a hammer for someone to catch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your wrist relaxed throughout and do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; consciously rotate the racquet face.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; important, and but it’s hard to get right initially.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You may hit a few balls over the fence, but don’t let that dissuade you.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Keep in mind that you are likely trying to &lt;em&gt;unlearn&lt;/em&gt; what you’ve been doing for a while.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;natural pronation&lt;/em&gt; of your wrist will take care of rotating the racquet face in time to meet the ball with the racquet face facing the court.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initially, just focus on the biomechanics and rhythm of the movement, and ignore where the ball actually lands. You can work on that easily later once you’ve got the mechanics going.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/Y1C6V_3s4nA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Explanation of tennis serve pronation.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you’ll soon notice is that you’ll start to see much better racquet head speed on your serves, and movement will be more effortless. In fact, if you observe the videos of Sampras serving closely enough, you’ll see how his wrist drops all the way pronated outwards after his ‘snap’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/4DpptgXq5j4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;The Sampras serve and pronation in action.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope these are useful to you. Please chime in via the comments, or let me know on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/three-tennis-serve-tips-i-wish-i-had-known-earlier.html&quot;&gt;Three Tennis Serve Tips I Wish I Had Known Earlier&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on January 10, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Droidcon Bigger Better]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/making-droidcon-bigger-better.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/making-droidcon-bigger-better</id>
  <published>2013-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//droidcon.in&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;static/images/droidcon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Droidcon India&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://droidcon.in/2013/&quot;&gt;Droidcon&lt;/a&gt; is India’s largest Android conference, and is part of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://droidcon.com/&quot;&gt;international chain&lt;/a&gt; of Droidcon conferences that happen in &lt;a href=&quot;http://de.droidcon.com/&quot;&gt;Berlin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://fr.droidcon.com/&quot;&gt;Paris&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://uk.droidcon.com/&quot;&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://es.droidcon.com/&quot;&gt;Madrid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ro.droidcon.com/&quot;&gt;Bucharest&lt;/a&gt; and other cities around the world. The event is organized by my good friends &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jackerhack&quot;&gt;Kiran&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zainabbawa&quot;&gt;Zainab&lt;/a&gt;, and their tireless team at &lt;a href=&quot;www.hasgeek.in&quot;&gt;HasGeek&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the third year now (&lt;a href=&quot;https://droidcon.in/2011/&quot;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://droidcon.in/2012/&quot;&gt;2012&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://droidcon.in/2013/&quot;&gt;2013&lt;/a&gt;), I’m reprising my role as the Program Chair, working with a committee of industry and community experts who volunteer their time to assist with setting the vision for the conference, developing themes, identifying great speakers, and curating their content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s never been an easy role volunteering for. Life at &lt;a href=&quot;//levitum.com&quot;&gt;Levitum&lt;/a&gt; has always been hectic as all startups are, offering limited time for social responsibilities. Both &lt;a href=&quot;//www.musiguru.in&quot;&gt;Musiguru&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;//www.singr.in&quot;&gt;Singr&lt;/a&gt; are in a major growth phase, and we have other initiatives in alpha. Also, since &lt;a href=&quot;//www.projectemm.com&quot;&gt;Monami&lt;/a&gt; is busy with her private art gallery and studio (she works Saturdays as well), we try to make the most of time we have together. This invariably leaves me with a lot less time for community events, and borrowed time usually means dropping something else on our list. The last two years, it’s taken a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of long days and nights in the month leading up to Droidcon to pull things together, and a lot of flexibility from others at home and work to support me. &lt;em&gt;This is just a shout out to say how much I appreciate them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;plan&quot;&gt;2013 Plan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.droidcon.in&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;static/images/meme_advanced_topics.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;More advanced topics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we’re really pushing ourselves to make Droidcon &lt;em&gt;bigger&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt;. In an effort to retain our sanity and those of people around us while doing so, we’ve begun preps sufficiently in advance so that there’s more time for everything. We’re also aware of the fatigue that accompanies conference season, and are looking for speakers that have &lt;em&gt;fresh&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; things to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing we’ve done differently is we’ve broken things into separate tracks. Two of the tracks will run in parallel at any point, presenting attendees from various streams with sufficient choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;systems&quot;&gt;Systems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Systems track runs across two days, and covers &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; aspects of the Android stack. Its being run by &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/kumrr&quot;&gt;Kumar&lt;/a&gt; of the LittleEyeLabs team. I’m so impressed by these guys, they should totally be running the &lt;em&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; event instead of me. There’s a ton of stuff to cover here, and they are already reaching to a number of folks to provide breadth and depth to the track. &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/gauravl&quot;&gt;Gaurav’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gauravl/status/381336687646752768&quot;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/koush&quot;&gt;Koushik&lt;/a&gt; got a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gauravl/status/381336687646752768&quot;&gt;buzz&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter, and we’re hoping to bring him down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be some overlap between Workshops &amp;amp; Systems with some of the advanced hands on session being broken out as longer workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“ We need more advanced, in depth talks ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This shall give the speakers an opportunity to do code walkthroughs and guide attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recurring theme at every Droidcon has been the need to help developers understand how to build well designed apps, and to help young designers gain more exposure and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“ We get technology, but not design ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I roped in my friend &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/gonsalves_r&quot;&gt;Rahul&lt;/a&gt; of Uncommon to help steer the design track. He is currently considering running a UX panel discussion followed by three speaker sessions - beginner, intermediate and advanced level sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.android.com/google/play-services/games.html&quot;&gt;Google Play Game Services&lt;/a&gt; were announced, everyones been dying to figure out how to take advantage of all the new cool additions. &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/ravikorukonda&quot;&gt;Ravi&lt;/a&gt; of PurpleTalk, who was also on the committee during the first Droidcon rejoins us to help drive a forward looking gaming track. Expect to see some of the top game developers come forward to share their experiences and plans. Ravi is planning on one panel discussion, and a few speaker sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;business&quot;&gt;Business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re bringing together product managers, advertisers, OEMs, and investors to the same table to offer a 360º view of the Android ecosystem. Expect discussion about product development lifecycles, marketing tips and tricks, new emerging trends at a macro level, monetization tips, and how you can build a business around building Android apps. I’ll be running this track with some assistance from &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/pacificleo&quot;&gt;Prashant&lt;/a&gt; of Signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things we’re conscious of is that this is a developer event. So, we’re keen to bring forward business speakers who can present insights that are relevant to the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possible panels I’m considering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://funnel.hasgeek.com/droidcon2013/877-panel-android-the-elephant-in-the-room-monetizatio&quot;&gt;Android &amp;amp; Monetization - The Elephant in the Room&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://funnel.hasgeek.com/droidcon2013/878-panel-how-can-i-get-wider-distribution-for-my-app&quot;&gt;Getting wider distribution for your apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://funnel.hasgeek.com/droidcon2013/879-panel-how-should-i-prep-for-my-app-launch&quot;&gt;How do you prep for your app launch?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://funnel.hasgeek.com/droidcon2013/880-panel-move-fast-break-things-or-polish-the-back-of&quot;&gt;Move fast, break things (OR) Polish the back of the furniture?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve reached out so far to Cleartrip, Hike, RedBus for Product Managers, and they have all expressed an interest in being involved. Next, I’ll be reaching out to InMobi and Flurry for advertising speakers. And then to a mix of app development startups with interesting monetization models or stories to tell. We will attempt to round off the ecosystem mix with Morpheus, Sony, Amazon and Intel depending on the availability of their speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not yet completely clear until we’ve nailed down more specifics, but we will experiment with at least one panel discussion and a few short speaker sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;app-demos&quot;&gt;App Demos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;App Demos is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; platform to showcase your app. &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/amsanjeev&quot;&gt;Amrit&lt;/a&gt; is reaching out to developers from across the country to come show &lt;em&gt;original&lt;/em&gt; work, and talk about specific challenges they have faced. This shall be a rapid fire track with short 15 minute nuggets of wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hands-on-workshops&quot;&gt;Hands-on Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other popular request last year was for more hands on sessions. People enjoyed 30-45 minute talks, but wanted to hear certain &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; speakers dig in and walk them through things in more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the good news is - We’re planning on a lot more 90-120 minute hands on workshops this year. Soham is working towards developing a series of run up workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be at least a whole day of beginner level workshops led by &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/s0h4m&quot;&gt;Soham&lt;/a&gt; and a few others, and at least half day of advanced workshops. &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/makash&quot;&gt;TWASG&lt;/a&gt; is planning a deep dive session on Android &amp;amp; security, and Gaurav is planning a session on battery optimization &amp;amp; networking. I’m hoping we can convince Satyam, Anenth, and Kavitha to also propose workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hackdays--hacknights&quot;&gt;Hackdays &amp;amp; Hacknights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year’s hacknight was wildly successful, and we’re planning a whole series of them this year including 2-3 in Bangalore. And oh, it’s not just Bangalore that’s getting all the love. Look out for Droidcon hacknights coming to Chennai, Hyderabad, Delhi, Pune, and Kochi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;collaboration&quot;&gt;Collaboration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//funnel.hasgeek.com/droidcon2013&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;static/images/meme_mouth_shut.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Make Friends!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is quite personal for me. I find that most tech conferences with multiple tracks can be a session treadmill. People dash between rooms from one talk to another, much like commuters on Mumbai’s busy trains.  While some conferences have designated spaces where people can hangout, AFAIK there’s limited focus or interest in really &lt;em&gt;enabling&lt;/em&gt; those spaces where people can get to know each other, collaborate, and find similar hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the thoughts this year is to create separate meeting spaces at the venue for at least a few of the primary tracks (Systems, Design, Gaming, Business). The MLR Convention Center in Whitefield has a number of little nooks - a mezzanine floor, a cozy room, and patio areas that would be fun areas to congregate. This would open out a number of possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re planning on coordinating with interested speakers to set up published office hours for each of the spaces (as a part of the schedule) during which they would be available for interaction at the space. This would provide an opportunity for those interested to go hangout there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explored this with Rahul, who had also some novel ideas for the Design space such as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;setting up a small installation which would play a few videos, which can be watched simultaneously by multiple people using headsets. This then becomes an ice breaker for them to discuss an idea further.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;providing wall area, sheets of paper and a bunch of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uistencils.com/products/android-stencil-kit&quot;&gt;Android Stencils&lt;/a&gt; lying around for people to conceptualize ideas and use the space as they’d like to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few ideas for the Systems space are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;organizing a Google I/O style treasure hunt with NFC tags &amp;amp; phones. &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;Ping me&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like to help with this. Intel’s software division has volunteered one of their core NFC guys to help out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;providing a projector &amp;amp; whiteboard space for brainstorming and code walkthroughs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also an incredibly &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; idea that I’ve run by Kiran &amp;amp; Zainab that they are looking into. If they can make it happen, I think it’ll be a blast, but I’m not holding my breath since there’s already a ton of things to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges with multiple tracks is that people end up having to choose. And often enough, they end up wishing they had been at the other session. There’s always &lt;a href=&quot;www.hasgeek.tv&quot;&gt;HasGeek TV&lt;/a&gt; so you can watch the videos of sessions you missed later on. But there’s another idea I’m toying with and need more feedback on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;starting the day with one hour of lightning talks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;each of the days’ speakers makes a 5 minute introduction to the topic they plan to present (later in the day).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audience gets a quick preview of what to expect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;can make a slightly more informed choice about which track and session they would like to be at.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be interesting to start the day with a networking breakfast for the speakers so that we can get everyone together, and then go from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-you-can-help&quot;&gt;How you can help&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//funnel.hasgeek.com/droidcon2013&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;static/images/meme_submit_proposals.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Submit a Proposal!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community events are all about the community, and depend greatly on those around being willing to give back to the community that has helped them. We’ve been fortunate to have had great speakers come forward from the community and share their knowledge and learnings. Everybody wins in a vibrant community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a speaker, here’s a few things you can do to help out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide a detailed speaker bio which helps the community understand why you are the best person for that talk. Include speaker bios, links to past videos or slides, and links to reference material.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide a slide outline early. Use sites like &lt;a href=&quot;//slid.es&quot;&gt;Slid.es&lt;/a&gt; which enable you to easily publish a link to work in progress drafts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep your audience in mind, pace your self, and ensure you have sufficient material to keep them engaged throughout.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be open to feedback and suggestions from the community and committee - remember that they are taking time out to help you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make yourself available to engage with the audience offline after the talk. Motivate and inspire others around you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an attendee, here’s a few things you can to do to help out&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vote for the speakers you like early in the process via the &lt;a href=&quot;//funnel.hasgeek.com/droidcon2013&quot;&gt;Droidcon Funnel&lt;/a&gt;. While it may appear that some speakers attempt to game the system by having their friends, family and dog vote for them, the Program Committee separately accounts for the subset of votes from those who are &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; attending the conference. Gotcha, gamers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If what you are looking for is hands on training, plan on attending the pre-conference workshops. Conference sessions can provide insight into new things and help with direction and resources, but are not meant to be full on training sessions. We’re planning these workshops precisely to cater to those would like to dig in further. Note that workshops require pre-registration since we are limiting capacity to ensure there’s sufficient training time devoted for each individual.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skip a few sessions. Seriously. Go hang out in the difference spaces created for each track so that you can interact directly with others (including the speakers). Make a few new friends, find things in common &amp;amp; have a good time. Don’t miss the event party - it’s always a fun place to catch up with others away from the conference.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognize that this is a community driven event. If you dont see topics being submitted in areas that interest you, either
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;come forward and &lt;em&gt;propose a topic yourself&lt;/em&gt;. If you dont fancy yourself as an expert in the area, consider a beginner level session proposal. You’d still have an impact on a large audience, and may be amazed at how much more you may connect with people than the experts from their ivory towers.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;nudge good speakers you’d like to see at Droidcon like what Gaurav did &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gauravl/status/381336687646752768&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to say you’re a fan of their work. &lt;em&gt;After all, who doesnt love their fans?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have more suggestions or feedback? Speak easy in the comments or feel free to ping me or the other committee members on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aravind Krishnaswamy is Co-Founder, &lt;a href=&quot;//levitum.com&quot;&gt;Levitum&lt;/a&gt;. He is a volunteer at &lt;a href=&quot;//droidcon.in&quot;&gt;Droidcon&lt;/a&gt;, and chairs the Program Committee&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/making-droidcon-bigger-better.html&quot;&gt;Making Droidcon Bigger Better&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on September 25, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Pycon]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://arg0s.in/my-first-pycon.html" />
  <id>http://arg0s.in/my-first-pycon</id>
  <published>2013-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  <updated>2013-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Arvi Krishnaswamy</name>
    <uri>http://arg0s.in</uri>
    <email>arvi@alumni.iastate.edu</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Late last month, &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/vinuthomas&quot;&gt;Vinu&lt;/a&gt;, Aditya, Jay and I attended &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/pyconindia&quot;&gt;Pycon India&lt;/a&gt; for the first time. I made a presentation about the technology stack we use at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.levitum.com&quot;&gt;Levitum&lt;/a&gt; for the backend some of our apps. We use a heady cocktail of &lt;code&gt;Flask&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Redis&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;CouchDB&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Postgres&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Heroku&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Gunicorn&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Gevent&lt;/code&gt; and have several hundred thousand users using the apps we’ve built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok there, I just tossed out a bunch of buzz words to make this post sound cool. But read on anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kennethreitz&quot;&gt;@kennethreitz&lt;/a&gt; for the appreciation of my talk at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pyconindia&quot;&gt;@pyconindia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23pyconindia&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;#pyconindia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23pyconindia2013&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;#pyconindia2013&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/IHhAdSgaND&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/IHhAdSgaND&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Aravind Krishnaswamy (@twitortat) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat/statuses/374078828915613696&quot;&gt;September 1, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/kennethreitz&quot;&gt;Kenneth Reitz&lt;/a&gt;, the python honcho at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.heroku.com&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; was impressed enough to give me a $300 gift card. Kenneth told me normally gives out $10-$25 cards, and I’m only the &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; person to receive one. So clearly, I must be good PR for Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my slides from the talk, powered by the nifty &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slid.es&quot;&gt;Slid.es&lt;/a&gt;. I picked up a Pro account with them so I could use my slides offline and not deal with Murphys law kicking in with conference Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://slid.es/arg0s/chugging-flask/embed&quot; width=&quot;576&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like the slides, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/swRtWJLUmLI&quot;&gt;full video&lt;/a&gt; on Youtube. And if you like the video as well, give me a shout in the comments. I ended up packing in way too much gyaan, and ran out of time. Next time, it’d probably make sense to break these into individual talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, a bunch of people enjoyed it. I touched upon a number of resources which I hope provide direction for others to dig into further and inspire them explore things on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, over 400 views of the slide deck. And plenty of kudos on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always wanted to know about FLASK and HHEROKU. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt; for giving a good insight. Credits to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23pyconindia2013&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;#pyconindia2013&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Ritesh Bhat (@Ritesh_Bhat) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Ritesh_Bhat/statuses/373685329930117120&quot;&gt;August 31, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Awesome talk from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23PyConIndia2013&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;#PyConIndia2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Suplab Debnath (@beingsuplab) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/beingsuplab/statuses/373685406044131328&quot;&gt;August 31, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt; some great random gyaan there. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23pyconindia&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;#pyconindia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Chitra Singh (@chit_raa) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/chit_raa/statuses/373684946772045824&quot;&gt;August 31, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Great bit of gyaan by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt; ! &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23pyconindia2013&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;#pyconindia2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Yes! The Seeker (@90sManiac) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/90sManiac/statuses/373719997941436417&quot;&gt;August 31, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt; btw awsome research done and nice presentation... :D&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Pankaj Anand (@Pankajanand26) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Pankajanand26/statuses/373730486440300544&quot;&gt;August 31, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good insights on how powerful can a micro framework like flask be. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23pyconindia2013&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;#pyconindia2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Suganthi (@enthudrives) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/enthudrives/statuses/373689802815569920&quot;&gt;August 31, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Best talks of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23PyConIndia2013&amp;amp;src=hash&quot;&gt;#PyConIndia2013&lt;/a&gt; Day 2 : chugging flask by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/twitortat&quot;&gt;@twitortat&lt;/a&gt; and ZeroMQ by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cnu&quot;&gt;@cnu&lt;/a&gt;. Most other talks were advertisement by sponsors&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Salil Panikkaveettil (@salilpa) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/salilpa/statuses/373835754373263360&quot;&gt;August 31, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks everyone for all the love. &lt;em&gt;You&lt;/em&gt; made all the hard work that went into the prep &lt;em&gt;totally&lt;/em&gt; worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/vinuthomas&quot;&gt;Vinu&lt;/a&gt;, Jay, &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/jackerhack&quot;&gt;Kiran&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;//twitter.com/noufalibrahim&quot;&gt;Noufal&lt;/a&gt; for their feedback on the slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of great things about the conference&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There were over a 1000 people. That’s huge for an event that’s totally community volunteer driven. Blows my mind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After my talk, a number of interesting people came by and engaged in insightful conversations. Made a bunch of new friends.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lots of terrific speakers who came well prepared, and delivered engaging, structured presentations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazed to see how python is now being used in so many different ways. Even &lt;a href=&quot;http://mpi4py.scipy.org/docs/usrman/intro.html#what-is-mpi&quot;&gt;MPI&lt;/a&gt; has a python layer now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kiran &amp;amp; Kenneth delivered outstanding keynotes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’d love to know who catered the lunch. I dont think I met anyone who didnt like it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conference wi-fi actually held out throughout, which seems to be a rarity at other events.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For a change, a lot of the sponsored booths were quite interesting and it was nice to go around and talk to them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IMO, The only downside of python becoming as big as it is now, is that there were &lt;a href=&quot;http://in.pycon.org/funnel/2013/88-predicting-black-swan-events&quot;&gt;certain topics&lt;/a&gt; where I probably followed less than 1/3rd of what the knowledgable speaker was presenting due to the nature of the problem domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s arguably good to be exposed to new topics, I wonder whether it may have been beneficial to have the schedule grouped into topics such as&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;python for newbies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;python &amp;amp; web&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;python language and its intricacies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;python &amp;amp; scientific community&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;python 3.x&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;python &amp;amp; devops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would arguably provide more focus and depth to each of these areas. And in between these, you’d have larger blocks of free time to socialize &amp;amp; just chill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, maybe it’s just me that feels this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invariably, there’s always tradeoffs between single-track vs multiple-track vs mish-mash. You cant make everyone happy, and shouldnt try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great job by the organizers. Congrats for making Pycon 2013 a great success.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in/my-first-pycon.html&quot;&gt;My First Pycon&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Arvi Krishnaswamy at &lt;a href=&quot;http://arg0s.in&quot;&gt;Arvi's Blog&lt;/a&gt; on September 19, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
